<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Aditya Unfiltered</title>
    <link>https://adi4blogs.netlify.app/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Aditya Unfiltered</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 27 Oct 2024 23:33:27 +0800</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://adi4blogs.netlify.app/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Time</title>
      <link>https://adi4blogs.netlify.app/posts/blog-entry-17/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 27 Oct 2024 23:33:27 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://adi4blogs.netlify.app/posts/blog-entry-17/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;image.png&#34; alt=&#34;&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I thought about writing a technical blog, but the illusion of having too much work this week stopped me from using my time wisely. Let&amp;rsquo;s talk about that.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We often feel overwhelmed by our workload. When we finish a task, we think we deserve a break. Yet, even if the workload isn&amp;rsquo;t that heavy and we have plenty of time left, we still feel mentally exhausted. The brain works in funny ways!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When you have a lot on your plate, your mind races with everything you want to do when you have free time. But for me, any free time I have (the kind I&amp;rsquo;m not tracking) passes by quickly. Isn&amp;rsquo;t it interesting how the semantics of time work? Time flies when you&amp;rsquo;re not thinking about it. But the moment you start to pay attention, it feels like it slows down. For example, I can hear my heartbeat when running, but my eyes are glued to the treadmill timer. I&amp;rsquo;m just waiting for those 20 minutes to pass, and it feels like I&amp;rsquo;ve run a marathon!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now, considering time as a dimension, general relativity tells us that time dilation occurs when moving at high speeds or being in a strong gravitational field. This is indeed a correct application of the theory. But is that all there is to it? Are there other factors influencing time dilation?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In physics, there&amp;rsquo;s a concept called entropy, which helps us understand how energy spreads out and becomes less useful over time. This idea can be thought of as the &amp;ldquo;arrow of time&amp;rdquo;—as things move from order to disorder. You could say time helps determine how energy is used or wasted, even if time itself isn&amp;rsquo;t consumed.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There&amp;rsquo;s also the philosophical idea of eternalism, which suggests that past, present, and future all exist at once. So, rather than time &amp;ldquo;running out,&amp;rdquo; every moment is just there, and our experience of moving through time is like traveling through a library of moments that are already written. When we feel like we&amp;rsquo;re wasting time, it might just be our perception of moving through those moments.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In a similar vein, when we think about information, time can relate to how quickly we process and understand things. If we spend time on something unproductive, it might feel like we&amp;rsquo;re wasting it—kind of like when our devices slow down, and it takes forever to get anything done.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In quantum mechanics, there’s this idea called decoherence, where the tiny building blocks of reality interact with their surroundings, making things more predictable over time. It’s a bit like how a lively party turns into a quieter gathering as people leave; the chaos settles into order.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As I explore these ideas, I wonder if any of this is true. It’s hard to grasp, right? If time exists as a dimension, what about the rate at which it changes? If all moments in time are out there, does that mean the energy at any moment never really moves on?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The uncertainty of it all makes me skeptical. Each theory presents a compelling story, but they also raise more questions than answers. If time is an illusion, what is the reality we’re experiencing? And if our perception is merely a reflection of those timelines, can we ever truly waste it? But if we stop worrying about how much time we have or don&amp;rsquo;t have, we might find that there’s enough time for everything that truly matters.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Signing off,&lt;br&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/adi4comp&#34;&gt;Aditya Ranjan Jha&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Science of Writing Science</title>
      <link>https://adi4blogs.netlify.app/posts/blog-entry-16/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 20 Oct 2024 22:38:37 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://adi4blogs.netlify.app/posts/blog-entry-16/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;image.png&#34; alt=&#34;&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This week I learned something that feels like a superpower. It’s not easy to learn, and I don’t think there&amp;rsquo;s a course for it, but it’s one of those things that, once you realize, changes how you think forever. So, buckle up—this is the introduction to some very formal lessons coming up soon.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I spent this week writing for my project, and every time I sent a draft to my advisor, I thought I’d nailed it. I mean, &lt;em&gt;masterpiece&lt;/em&gt; level nailed it. I had heard my advisor was strict about scientific communication, and I’d seen how clear his course presentations were. But when I got his feedback&amp;hellip; well, it was the same feedback everyone in the lab seemed to get. The moment I understood his point, I was both fascinated by his insight and completely embarrassed by my writing. After three rounds of edits and about a week of back-and-forth, I finally wrote&amp;hellip; &lt;em&gt;drumroll&lt;/em&gt;&amp;hellip; two pages. Yes, two whole pages! But trust me, the mistakes and the process were invaluable lessons.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;the-reality-check-my-writing-was-not-good&#34;&gt;The Reality Check: My Writing Was… Not Good &lt;a href=&#34;#the-reality-check-my-writing-was-not-good&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;First off, I had this grand illusion that my thoughts were clear and my writing was top-notch. Yeah, no. That glass has shattered. What I thought was clarity was, in reality, a confusing mess. I realize now that this probably goes back to childhood habits. I was always a messy presenter of ideas—especially in handwritten work. I hated it so much that, as a teenager, I rarely even did my own projects. I’d ask my mom or sister to make them for me! I thought those assignments were about creativity or art. But in reality, they were teaching us how to present ideas in an organized, visual way. There are people who write answers by highlighting the key points first. And then there’s me, crafting sentences so &amp;ldquo;elegant&amp;rdquo; that the point gets lost entirely.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Thinking back, I can see why my university grades sometimes looked like crash test dummies. It wasn’t just my handwriting; my ideas were stuck in my brain and didn’t make it onto the paper. Twice, I even had professors on the verge of ripping up my answer sheets! At the time, I thought it was just about presentation or handwriting, but really, the problem was that I hadn’t written down what was actually in my head.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So, here I am, finally realizing I need to fix this. Better late than never, right? From now on, I’m making an effort to get better at scientific writing. I’m going to use my blog to convey ideas, and I’ll start sending drafts to people for feedback. I’ve learned that the core of scientific writing isn’t about showing off vocabulary (sorry, past me), but about getting ideas across clearly and directly.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;keep-it-simple-and-visual&#34;&gt;Keep It Simple (And Visual!) &lt;a href=&#34;#keep-it-simple-and-visual&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;The first rule of &lt;del&gt;fight&lt;/del&gt; write club? Keep sentences short. (If this blog seems ironic to you, well, just know I’m still learning!) Long sentences lose the reader, and that makes total sense. Another key? Write in order. The best texts allow the reader to build context by reading each line in sequence, without jumping all over the place. And, surprise surprise, the simpler the writing, the better. If someone with no background can understand your work, you&amp;rsquo;ve won. Unlike literary devices, where complexity might add depth, in science, it adds confusion. The best ideas should pop up right in the beginning, so the reader doesn’t get lost in unnecessary details.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Another thing I’ve learned is about maintaining context size—each word should be an abstraction of either a well-known concept or something from your own contribution. The fewer abstractions (verbs, nouns) you use to explain your idea, the clearer it becomes. Think of it like this: it’s all about how many key words you need to describe your idea accurately. And diagrams? They’re golden. A picture really does speak a thousand words—if it’s simple enough! Diagrams should communicate ideas as cleanly and minimally as possible. If you can follow all of this, wrap things up with a strong claim to leave an impression.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here’s the cool part: I now appreciate all the things I used to overlook. Diagrams in scientific texts, animations in videos, slides in presentations—each word spoken by a presenter has a purpose. It’s so difficult to encapsulate a whole idea in just a few minutes of talking or writing. And it’s not just short presentations—long ones are hard too, because people are more likely to zone out. The challenge is to keep their attention and communicate the core idea early.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Since joining this program, I’ve seen some excellent presentations. What stood out to me was how much time these presenters spent setting up the background. Only about 25% of the time was devoted to their actual contribution. This is exactly opposite of what our bachelor thesis presentations at KGP trained us for: spend most of the time on the results! I think the focus on results was about proving our sincerity, not the novelty of our ideas (especially since we only had 10 minutes to present).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So, yeah, this blog may not fully follow the lessons I’ve learned this week, but it’s a start. I’ll be writing more technical blogs from here on out, putting these new skills into practice. Stay tuned!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Signing off,&lt;br&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/adi4comp&#34;&gt;Aditya Ranjan Jha&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Something Cheerfully Gloomy</title>
      <link>https://adi4blogs.netlify.app/posts/blog-entry-15/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 14 Oct 2024 20:33:19 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://adi4blogs.netlify.app/posts/blog-entry-15/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;Cover.png&#34; alt=&#34;&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s late, and I feel like I&amp;rsquo;ve messed up my time management last week. I didn&amp;rsquo;t have anything concrete to write about, but for the sake of consistency—and because it&amp;rsquo;ll help me remember this moment—I&amp;rsquo;ve decided to pen down something abstract, even a bit gloomy. Despite the tone, the realization I had about it is important.
This week, after hearing the sad news of Shri Ratan Tata&amp;rsquo;s passing, I found myself reflecting on something abstract but deeply personal. I thought about his life, and suddenly, the most abstract and generic philosophy arose in my mind. It&amp;rsquo;s about what happiness really is. I know there are thousands of sources that define happiness differently, and some might even mock the question. But I&amp;rsquo;ve realized a definition that resonates with me uniquely and personally. I also know the tone of this text might seem like I&amp;rsquo;m trying to be just another wannabe philosopher, but here it goes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Happiness, I believe, is a fleeting period when the burdens of the past don&amp;rsquo;t weigh you down, and the future holds no looming expectations. It&amp;rsquo;s a moment in which you aren&amp;rsquo;t wishing for something better—whether it&amp;rsquo;s as brief as the joy of savoring your favorite food, or as long as a stretch of time in the past that you wish had never ended.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Looking back, one of those longer stretches of happiness for me was during the COVID lockdowns. I was with my family, safe, and everyone—including my dad—was working from home. Even though I was anxiously looking forward to future exams, I realize now that those were some of my happiest times. This contradiction is intentional because it leads to an important realization: Happiness isn&amp;rsquo;t static or absolute—it&amp;rsquo;s relative. A single event can carry both sadness and joy, depending on how you view it over time.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Another stretch of happiness came during the last two years, surrounded by friends, despite feeling burdened by uncertainty about my career and a tendency toward lethargy. Even though I was stuck in those feelings, I had the freedom to speak openly and enjoy the little moments with them—like our simple treks up and down the bridge near the tapri. During that time, I understood how fleeting such experiences were, knowing they would end soon. And when they did end, and I returned home, it felt like just another summer. But, I realize now how much I cherish those moments.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Since coming to Singapore, I&amp;rsquo;ve struggled to recreate that environment. I tried replacing those feelings with finding hobbies or by meeting new people, but nothing felt quite the same. When neither worked, I found myself clinging to the past, realizing—once again—that you can&amp;rsquo;t live in those moments forever. I recalled the &amp;ldquo;canon events&amp;rdquo; those defining moments when it all started, from our first interactions to every shared memory, regardless of whether they were captured in photos.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This reflection led me to the most generic question: Can we ever be happy forever? And then the most textbook answer came to me—&amp;ldquo;Change is the only constant.&amp;rdquo; It&amp;rsquo;s a truth that may seem sad, but it also makes sense. Without this constant change, I wouldn&amp;rsquo;t cherish the past or look forward to the future. While I can only connect the dots in hindsight, the fact that I&amp;rsquo;m reflecting on this now means I&amp;rsquo;m ready to embrace the next &amp;ldquo;canon events&amp;rdquo;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Although I still can&amp;rsquo;t figure out what we&amp;rsquo;re even doing in life. Running around trying to “make an impact,” while the people we actually want to keep around are… well, not around. It&amp;rsquo;s like, &amp;ldquo;Congrats, you&amp;rsquo;ve unlocked the &amp;rsquo;life goals&amp;rsquo; achievement! Too bad everyone you want to share it with is conveniently out of reach. Classic!&amp;rdquo; It makes you wonder—are we just collecting successes or secretly playing hide-and-seek with the universe?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I mean, sure, people say, “You&amp;rsquo;ll find new people to share this with,” and that&amp;rsquo;s great and all. But why does the old one have to be replaced? Sounds depressing, right? Well, don&amp;rsquo;t worry, I&amp;rsquo;ve got plenty of free time, so I overthink all of this for you. See you next week.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Signing off &lt;br&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/adi4comp&#34;&gt;Aditya Ranjan Jha&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Art of Glorifying the Grind</title>
      <link>https://adi4blogs.netlify.app/posts/blog-entry-14/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 06 Oct 2024 20:33:19 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://adi4blogs.netlify.app/posts/blog-entry-14/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;Cover.png&#34; alt=&#34;&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So, here’s the thing—I’ve got opinions. A lot of them. And this one? It’s a bit out there, but it’s helped me stop getting overwhelmed, so I’m sticking with it. Now, I know I’m not a native English speaker, but I’m still gonna take a crack at making this funny. So, bear with me—this is my attempt at turning my slightly weird take into something that’ll hopefully make you laugh (or at least nod along).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Disclaimer:&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;em&gt;If you feel offended at any point, just know I’m not targeting you. I’m just bored on a Saturday/Sunday evening and trying to add a little sass to my blogs.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You ever notice how everyone loves bragging about how hard they’re working? Like, hustle culture is a badge of honor now. But, have you ever stopped and thought—maybe, just maybe—they’re just not smart enough to do the work faster? I mean, come on. No one’s perfect. You probably wasted half your time googling how to do the thing you were supposed to be doing. I get it; we’ve all been there. But seriously, if everyone was that efficient, machine learning would be obsolete. Basically there&amp;rsquo;d be no field where people go, “Hey, you know what’s groundbreaking? Making the same mistake as the last model but 5% better!”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And don’t get me started on the glorification of certain habits—like coffee. It’s like a personality trait now. Every so-called genius is like, “Man, I can’t start my day without coffee. I need six cups just to function!” Really? That’s like a bodybuilder going, “Man, I can’t hit the gym without a shot of steroids—it makes me stronger!” And we’d all be like, “Umm…maybe that’s not the flex you think it is, dude.” But no, we see a guy with a laptop in one hand and a coffee in the other, and we’re like, “Wow, that’s the picture of success right there.” When really, we should be asking, “Why wasn’t he smart enough to finish his work on time and, y’know, get a full night’s sleep?” But instead, we’re all like, “Look at him! Burning the midnight oil. What a hustler.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Isn’t it funny how we love to glorify anything that makes us feel overwhelmed? Or worse, it gives us this weird resentment for our peers, like, “Why are they getting more than what they work for?” But hold on—what if they’re just&amp;hellip; better at managing their time? Maybe they get their work done on time, leave on time, and embrace themselves—don’t brag about it. Now, I get it. There’s another possibility: maybe they just have a different agenda. Like, let’s say you and your coworkers have a deadline coming up, and you’re thinking, “Wow, I’m definitely working harder than they are.” Well, there are two scenarios here. One, maybe they were just consistent enough to follow the timeline from the start (crazy, right?). Or two, maybe they straight up don’t care if they hit the deadline. In that case, their intent is different from yours. But what’s really funny is when people start flexing about how they’re hustling all weekend to meet the deadline. And I think the right question to ask would be, “Okay, but&amp;hellip;what were you doing all week?”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And this isn’t just about deadlines. This is the same energy as people who brag about how they get one day a week to &amp;ldquo;actually live.&amp;rdquo; Meanwhile, I’m seeing their stories every single day—humbly bragging about how hard their life is, but they’re not working either, so&amp;hellip; maybe just go home and live your life?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Then there are the complainers. You know the type—they’ll complain when they’re unemployed, complain when they get a travel job, complain when they have a desk job. It’s like a hobby at this point. And if that’s not bad enough, now we have social butterflies bragging about how introverted they are. How is that a flex? “Dude, I just have to grind and be different from the crowd, you know? The crowd is so lame.” Well, I’ve got news for you. The crowd’s not lame—you’re just an idiot.Because while you&amp;rsquo;re busy trying to be &amp;ldquo;different,&amp;rdquo; the crowd’s actually out there getting things done. They’re not overthinking how to look special or bragging about their struggles. They’re just working smarter, not harder.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The internet has made us absolutely insane. Like, you’ve got people out here showing off how hard they had to work to become successful, but if you look closely, half of them were just supervising. &amp;ldquo;I had to hustle for my dreams!&amp;rdquo; No, Karen, you just sat there making sure the people actually working were doing their jobs. Meanwhile, the real hard workers? They’re the ones who stay quiet, because they don’t have time to film their ‘grind’ for social media. They’re too busy getting stuff done.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And here’s the thing: when you love what you do, it doesn’t even feel like work. It just becomes part of your life. You don’t need to be shouting about how &amp;ldquo;overwhelmed&amp;rdquo; you are, because guess what? If you keep getting overwhelmed, maybe you&amp;rsquo;re just&amp;hellip; inefficient. That’s right. You want credit for suffering, but have you ever stopped to think, “Hmm, maybe I could’ve done this faster, or better, or with less crying?” No, of course not, because then you wouldn’t get to brag about how much you “sacrificed.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Honestly, if you’re not trying to get better at something, what’s the point of doing it over and over again? I learned to ask myself that whenever I felt overwhelmed. It became this internal voice, like, “Hey, calm down, maybe you’re just being stupid right now.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But the funniest part? We’re all out here desperate for credit—credit for suffering, credit for hustling. So what better way to make sense of this madness than to turn it into humor? Because really, what else can you do when everyone’s out here acting like their stress is a trophy?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Signing off &lt;br&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/adi4comp&#34;&gt;Aditya Ranjan Jha&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Navigating the Grey</title>
      <link>https://adi4blogs.netlify.app/posts/blog-entry-13/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 29 Sep 2024 21:33:19 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://adi4blogs.netlify.app/posts/blog-entry-13/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;cover.png&#34; alt=&#34;&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The other day, I was reflecting on kindness—why it’s important to do something kind every day. Kindness is a virtue, but expecting it from others can be a slippery slope. What we often forget is that the essence of kindness lies in not expecting anything in return: no redemption, no reward, just the simple act of giving because you feel you&amp;rsquo;ve received more than your share.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The trouble arises when we’re treated poorly. We start to question whether being kind is even worth it. The truth is, you can’t expect everyone to be kind. It’s a choice we each make, and we have to live with that choice. As the saying goes, &amp;ldquo;Either you die a hero, or you live long enough to see yourself become the villain.&amp;rdquo; The root cause of this disillusionment is often expectations. We hold people to unspoken standards—hoping they’ll behave in ways we deem ‘nice.’ But silent expectations are dangerous. If you want something, sometimes you need to say it out loud; other times, you simply need to accept people as they are.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you can do something kind without expecting anything in return, then do it. Don’t keep score. And if you’re looking for a reward, be upfront about it. Otherwise, maybe the action isn’t worth taking. This brings me to a personal struggle: ethics. Philosophers often say ethics are boundaries created by the weak to make themselves feel better. And when I think about whether I’m a good person or not, I come to a humbling realization—I have some of the wildest thoughts. Thoughts filled with petty rage, grudges, and other emotions I’m not proud of. But the key is, I don’t act on them. I do my best to control those urges and not let them dictate my decisions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I’ve come to see that it’s not all black and white. Life is more of a grey area. And that grey is often fueled by the volatility of my mind. Most of the time, I manage to keep things in check, though the frequency of losing control is higher than I’d like to admit. When that happens, I take a step back and reflect, and usually, I calm down—at least for a while. This cycle reminds me of when I struggled with stress-eating a year ago. I could control it for some time, but then, over the smallest trigger, I’d spiral out of control. Once I thought I’d crossed the line, I felt like I was already in the dark, so why not fully commit? But the truth is, I wasn’t in the dark—I was in the grey. There’s always a way back, always progress to be made. There are no losses, only lessons. And just like my fat-loss journey, I’d falter, then bounce back even stronger. Eventually, I got so far past the line that I could stay above it. (Though, to be honest, the journey is still ongoing.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There are other areas of my life I know I can improve. I’ve always struggled to find a balance between what’s good for my mind and what’s good for my personal growth. I’ve swung to the extreme ends of both, and I’m sure this is something many people can relate to in some part of their lives. It’s easy to feel like you can’t come back once you’ve gone too far, but the reality is that most of our actions lie in the grey zone. And in most cases, there’s always a way out.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For me, the best way out is sleep. Sleeping solves most of my problems. When I’m weighed down by my thoughts or my conscience, a good night’s sleep brings me clarity. It’s not meditation, but it’s effective for me. And I think that’s an important lesson: if you’re having a bad day, don’t give up so soon. It’s easy to forget that most good ideas don’t come from immediate breakthroughs. They emerge after hours of trial and error, often following silly mistakes. I used to feel the need to justify my process to others—explaining that I wasn’t just slacking off—but what I’ve learned from my time at NUS is that the final ideas aren’t the time-consuming part. It’s the wrong ideas that take time. It’s figuring out why they don’t work that demands so much energy.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Speaking of fragile minds, how often do we start down one path, only to realize halfway through that we’ve been wrong the entire time? For me, this happens frequently. I’ll be convinced I’m on the right track, only to suddenly realize I’ve been lost all along. I think the root cause is my tendency to imagine how the outcome will look, getting so wrapped up in the destination that I lose sight of the actual journey. I forget to evaluate whether I’m truly heading in the right direction, and by the time I recognize the detour, it feels like I’m too far gone. But even then, there’s a lesson: it’s not about how far off track you’ve gone, but about recognizing it and adjusting course. It’s all part of the grey area—there’s always a way to correct yourself if you’re willing to stop, rethink, and move forward with fresh insight.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Signing off &lt;br&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/adi4comp&#34;&gt;Aditya Ranjan Jha&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Lessons in Patience, Focus, and Output</title>
      <link>https://adi4blogs.netlify.app/posts/blog-entry-12/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 22 Sep 2024 22:34:20 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://adi4blogs.netlify.app/posts/blog-entry-12/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;image.png&#34; alt=&#34;&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The world has a strange way of humbling you, especially when you don’t realize you’re wrong. If you’re lucky enough, you’ll recognize what’s happening before it’s too late. Just last year, during an internship project, I found myself adapting to the problem statement much faster than my teammates. This gave me a sense of superiority—I used to get frustrated when they couldn’t keep up and contribute equally. I convinced myself that they weren’t putting in as much effort, which made it easy to look down on them for not pulling their weight.
At that time, I grew resistant to group projects where one person seems to do all the work while others bask in the success. However, life has a way of bringing you full circle. In my current project, I’m working on an exciting problem with a colleague who is much smarter, more organized, and meticulous than I am. This has been a humbling experience. While I sometimes feel disappointed when things don’t go my way or when I can’t lead from the front like I’m accustomed to, I recently realized how slow of a learner I am compared to him.
What struck me yesterday was how quickly he picked up concepts in a field that’s completely new to both of us, while I spent a whole week getting nowhere. In one hour of structured thinking, he helped me generalize a solution that took me days of effort to even brute-force. It gave me a strange sense of déjà vu, reminding me of my impatience during previous internships when I was in the stronger position.
I now realize that I had wrongly assumed my former colleagues weren’t trying as hard as I was. I didn’t take their learning speed into account. My colleague today is far more patient with me than I ever was with my teammates. I’m grateful for this realization, and all I can say is looking forward if I am in a similar position again, I will be much better.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;the-minds-maze-keeping-track-of-the-core-idea&#34;&gt;The Mind’s Maze: Keeping Track of the Core Idea &lt;a href=&#34;#the-minds-maze-keeping-track-of-the-core-idea&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;Another important realization I’ve had is how easily you can get lost in your thoughts, and how important it is to stay grounded. It’s all too common to lose track of the core idea when you’re deeply immersed in thought. This is why it’s crucial to note down important points—especially when you take a break.
When you write down what you’ve done and evaluate how much it contributes to the solution, it helps you recognize whether you’ve wandered off course. Successful people often say it’s easy to control your mind, but for me, trying to control a thought often leads to distractions. The mind works recursively, pulling you off-topic the moment you try to focus. Writing things down keeps you tethered so that even if you get lost, you can always return to your original line of thinking.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;output-over-input-finding-a-balance&#34;&gt;Output Over Input: Finding a Balance &lt;a href=&#34;#output-over-input-finding-a-balance&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;Recently, someone told me, &amp;ldquo;Nobody cares about the input; everyone wants the output.&amp;rdquo; As intimidating as that sounds, it’s true. You can use this mindset to stay productive by constantly thinking about how your actions contribute to the final result. But it’s not always the best approach. Sometimes, when you can&amp;rsquo;t see a fully formed solution, you waste time trying to force it.
Sometimes, when a solution feels trivial or intuitive, it wasn’t truly intuitive—it only seems that way because you’ve built up the necessary knowledge base through hard work and trial and error. The wrong paths you take still add to your understanding.
So, when is the &amp;ldquo;output over input&amp;rdquo; mindset useful? It helps when you start feeling overwhelmed by the effort required to reach a solution. From the outside, the final result might look simple and intuitive, but you know the depth of effort behind it. Keeping your focus on the output can help you push through without letting the difficulty of the process slow you down.
A perfect example is Albert Einstein. When he developed the theory of general relativity, it might seem obvious to us today, but it wasn’t intuitive back then. He spent nearly a decade wrestling with complex mathematics, rethinking assumptions, and even seeking help from others. The journey was long, but Einstein didn’t get caught up in the difficulty. He remained focused on the result. Even after achieving success in 1919, Einstein didn’t rest. He continued pushing boundaries, tackling new challenges like quantum mechanics and the search for a unified field theory.
Einstein’s ability to focus on the output, rather than getting bogged down by the input, serves as a powerful reminder. Sometimes, we get overwhelmed by the effort, but by keeping our eyes on the outcome, we can keep moving forward.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Signing off &lt;br&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/adi4comp&#34;&gt;Aditya Ranjan Jha&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Regrets</title>
      <link>https://adi4blogs.netlify.app/posts/blog-entry-11/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 14 Sep 2024 09:33:19 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://adi4blogs.netlify.app/posts/blog-entry-11/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;Cover.png&#34; alt=&#34;&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Note: The phrase &amp;ldquo;In most cases&amp;rdquo; is implied throughout the blog&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The other day, I was returning from the lab and started evaluating if what I’m doing is right—whether it will contribute to my goals or not. I wondered, &amp;ldquo;What if I regret picking this project? What if it doesn’t turn out the way I want?&amp;rdquo; After thinking about it for a few minutes, I started reflecting on all the times in the past where I couldn’t see the road ahead clearly. Interestingly, this brought me to a larger, more abstract question that many of us have faced in one form or another: &lt;strong&gt;&amp;ldquo;Do I regret making this choice, or do I just wish something had been different that could’ve made my situation better?&amp;rdquo;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It’s a common feeling—regretting a choice and wasting time imagining alternate scenarios where things might have turned out better. We’ve all been there. In one line, you could say, &amp;ldquo;The grass is always greener on the other side.&amp;rdquo; But if I were to give my analysis (and because this is my blog), here’s my take:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When we make important life choices—like deciding between two different paths—it’s natural to spend time carefully considering our options. We use our intuition, analyze potential outcomes, and try to predict what will bring us the most happiness. However, no matter how much time we spend or how thoroughly we think things through, the true outcome of our decisions is often shaped by &lt;strong&gt;uncontrollable factors&lt;/strong&gt;—random events, external influences, and life circumstances we simply can’t predict.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Regret tends to come up when the outcome doesn’t match our expectations. But here’s the catch: no matter how much time or effort we put into the decision, we can’t fully predict the future. Our predictions are based on limited information and are often biased by our preferences. The true outcome is influenced by unknown factors beyond our control. So, the regret we feel—or the satisfaction we experience—has little to do with the decision process itself.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the end, the &lt;strong&gt;time spent making the decision&lt;/strong&gt; and the &lt;strong&gt;methods used&lt;/strong&gt;—whether instinctive or analytical—become irrelevant to the final outcome. Regret, then, is often misplaced because the real factors that shaped the outcome were &lt;strong&gt;unpredictable&lt;/strong&gt; from the start.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For example, imagine you’re in your 20s and are given a choice between leading an active social lifestyle (the &amp;ldquo;YOLO&amp;rdquo; crowd) or isolating yourself to work on self-improvement and your career (the &amp;ldquo;make an impact&amp;rdquo; kind of people). Neither path guarantees happiness. No matter what choice you make, at some point, you’ll have made a wrong move along the way. And you’ll wonder: &lt;strong&gt;&amp;ldquo;What if I’d done things differently?&amp;rdquo;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This happens because satisfaction isn’t just a function of the actual outcome. It’s &lt;strong&gt;inversely proportional&lt;/strong&gt; to the gap between your expectations and reality. And we all know that we tend to keep raising our expectations. That’s why you’ll rarely meet someone who hasn’t thought, &amp;ldquo;Life would be better if I’d made a different choice.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you’re going through a rough time and can’t wait for it to end, don’t challenge the universe. Things might get even worse, and you could find yourself missing the very moment you once wanted to escape. So, is it impossible to ever be happy? No, it’s not. The key is to &lt;strong&gt;enjoy the process&lt;/strong&gt; and learn to live with whatever outcome follows. In the end, most of us realize that it all connects—you can always look back and connect the dots. If you believe that there will come a time when things are better, start telling yourself that everything makes sense now, and you’ll get there faster.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I came to this conclusion when I was optimizing my trips using public transportation to run errands. I realized that there was always a bus I could’ve caught earlier, even when I thought I’d caught the best one by running and barely making it on time. It was a self-taught lesson that helps me stop worrying about the past in most cases. Of course, I still make mistakes more often than I’d like to admit, but writing this down at least makes me feel better going into the next week.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Signing off &lt;br&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/adi4comp&#34;&gt;Aditya Ranjan Jha&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Introduction 2.0</title>
      <link>https://adi4blogs.netlify.app/posts/blog-entry-10/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 08 Sep 2024 10:42:51 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://adi4blogs.netlify.app/posts/blog-entry-10/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;Cover.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Well, it&amp;rsquo;s been over eight months since I last wrote a blog and a full year since I promised to make serious changes in my life. Things have been going well since then: physically, I’m in much better shape, and mentally, I’m driven without feeling guilty, so that’s a win. Over the past year, I’ve had several moments of celebration, but there’s still a feeling of incompleteness that I’d like to address. I think I’ve made some additional lifestyle changes that could be beneficial for my personal growth. While I can’t encapsulate everything that’s happened in the last eight months just yet—perhaps I’ll save that for the year-end blog—what I can do now is fast forward to today and present a new version of myself. I aim to be more regular with my upcoming blogs, a bit more unfiltered, more vocal, and happier about what I’ve accomplished, while still being as reflective about my mistakes as before.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;present-day&#34;&gt;Present Day &lt;a href=&#34;#present-day&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;I’ve joined the National University of Singapore’s School of Computing (PhD) after completing my bachelors among the best bunch of peers and friends from IIT Kharagpur. My first project is in the field of Programming Languages (PL), which is entirely new to me. My lab group has been incredibly patient with my slow adaptation to this learning curve. Although I find brainstorming interesting after such a long time, I miss the hands-on aspect of implementing and executing projects. Nevertheless, I believe that reading and conducting literature reviews are crucial parts of the learning process for junior PhDs. The field of PL is intriguing; it seems to be the only area of systems with a formal proof, though I might just be unfamiliar with other areas. Being unaware reminds me of how naive I was about research and the role of an advisor. I used to hold some ill-informed opinions about life that made me feel self-assured (perhaps overly opinionated), but I was simply naive. I can’t publicly acknowledge all of those opinions, but if I ever said something that seemed too strong or foolish, I hope you’ll forgive me. I’ve realized a lot about my previous views.
Back to Singapore—I’ve been here for a month now and am still trying to find a good social circle. The lab group is fantastic, so I spend most of my time there and then retreat to my apartment to sleep. One of the changes I’ve decided to make in this new version of myself is quitting digital media, which makes finding activities to fill my free time more challenging, except for phone calls with friends and family.
After a month here, I find myself believing more and more in destiny. The advisor and lab environment are a perfect fit for me, despite my initial concerns based on reviews from my professors. I’ve had a lot of time to reflect and realize that I need to work towards creating an impact or solving a significant problem. My advisor has extensive experience in training and is very candid with his feedback. It feels like luck to land in such an environment. While my beliefs may evolve over time, one thing I’m certain of is that I wouldn’t change any of my past experiences because they’ve all contributed to the person I am today, and I feel I have a purpose.
One area I want to work on is my social anxiety. Although I’m not an introvert, I’ve struggled with finding words or icebreakers when meeting new people lately. This might be due to a lack of social interaction recently, but I need to change that. It’s not a language barrier, but rather my own apprehensions about saying too much or whether people will understand me that hold me back.
Living in Singapore has had its inconveniences at first, especially with formalities (I just completed mine a few days ago). However, other aspects, like food and the overall student-friendliness, are very convenient. So, good night for now. I’m tired, but I think this sums up my current state. Next week, I’ll dive into more specifics—maybe about my work, goals, or other topics. Or perhaps I’ll share some thoughts on life that I might later find amusingly misguided.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Signing off &lt;br&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/adi4comp&#34;&gt;Aditya Ranjan Jha&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>2k23 Wrapped Up!</title>
      <link>https://adi4blogs.netlify.app/posts/blog-entry-09/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 Dec 2023 22:41:08 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://adi4blogs.netlify.app/posts/blog-entry-09/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;cover.png&#34; alt=&#34;&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At the end of last year, I was filled with hopes of capitalizing on the opportunities that came my way. Throughout this year, at every juncture, I believed things couldn&amp;rsquo;t get any better, yet they continued to improve. Although I hadn&amp;rsquo;t planned for specific career milestones, I did achieve some along the way. My primary goal was to confront my inner demons and address personal challenges. While I successfully resolved many of them, there were some that proved more elusive.One persistent challenge has been maintaining discipline, and my initial attempt involved a commitment to daily bathing, even in the frigid -4 degrees Celsius weather. Despite a strong start, I faltered and broke the resolution somewhere in the second month of the year. However, in the early second half of the year, I made a conscious decision to transform my life positively. Reflecting on my journey, I realized that using my blog as an outlet to vent and confess my flaws wasn&amp;rsquo;t conducive to personal growth. Consequently, I chose to pause writing blogs until I addressed some of my character flaws and could share happier news or personal milestones. Reading my blogs felt like a one-sided therapy session, and I wanted to shift the narrative.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;While I don&amp;rsquo;t have joyous news to share at the moment, I aim to end the year on a positive note. I acknowledge that this blog may still sound somber, but forgive me as I attempt to infuse it with a more optimistic tone. I will also be more informative about the subjects of discussion, unlike last year.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This year kicked off with a delightful trip to Bhutan, a tranquil and serene place that felt like the perfect retirement home. While I was there, the looming thought of returning to the two projects I had recently started crept into my mind. However, since my return, I&amp;rsquo;ve been using the visuals from my trip for meditation or just to release those happy chemicals in my brain. Upon my return, I dove into working on two projects simultaneously. While I found joy in the embedded security project with a startup, the other project left me a bit disheartened due to inconclusive results. I made an effort to lead a disciplined life, juggling classes and balancing both projects. As the college fests rolled around, I unfortunately missed Kshitij Tech Fest due to work commitments. Then came Spring Fest, where on day 0, I found myself alone at the night concert. Somehow, I got separated from my friends, and a feeling of loneliness crept in. Sensing that the coming days might be similar, I impulsively decided to head back home.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;During this time, I also received an offer from one of my MITACS projects. It&amp;rsquo;s worth noting that when I applied for research fellowships, I was heavily involved in a High-Performance Computing (HPC) project. Consequently, my applications were mostly geared towards HPC and a few embedded projects. Despite not planning to accept HPC projects, as I wanted to stay close to hardware, I found myself in a dilemma when I received an offer for an Embedded Systems project. My field of interest broadly encompasses Computer Architecture and Embedded Systems, but most of my work experience until that point had been in embedded systems.Faced with this decision, I sought advice from various sources (a friend, a senior, and ChatGPT). After careful consideration, I chose to pursue the research internship, primarily for the recommendation letter, despite not having concrete plans to join the lab, which specialized in Network Research.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After gaining valuable exposure to automotive security and receiving appreciation for my work, along with promising results in my microarchitectural security project, I was geared up for my journey to Canada. Despite it being the longest flight of my life, I couldn&amp;rsquo;t fully enjoy the experience. Upon reaching there, Professor Jorg Liebeherr welcomed me warmly. I kicked off my time by utilizing the campus gym, but on the third day, I got scolded for being an hour late to the lab, unaware that I had a meeting with the Professor at 10 am that morning. However, since that incident, I made it a point to reach the lab before 10 am every day, contributing to a highly productive summer. While I couldn&amp;rsquo;t publish a paper based on my project, I did secure a robust recommendation letter and an offer to join the lab. Beyond the technical expertise gained, my stint in Canada taught me about the inner workings of a research group and the value of a close-knit, small research community. Despite feeling homesick throughout my time there, I didn&amp;rsquo;t engage much in city exploration, possibly due to a lack of confidence or a subconscious inclination to return home before dark. My routine consisted of waking up, cooking lunch and breakfast, heading to the lab, returning, and sleeping, often wasting weekends in the process.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This became my second abroad trip where I hindered my own experience due to laziness, unnecessary overthinking, and pedantic procrastination. However, I found solace and purpose in the lab environment, where I could immerse myself in work without worrying about external factors. Consequently, I started staying late, overworking, and indulging in fried junk food from campus food trucks, leading to a noticeable weight gain, perhaps exceeding 5 kgs. In the last month, I seized a long weekend (without missing a single work day) for a trip to Banff, a hill station in another part of Canada. The experience was somewhat awkward for me, being my first trip with friends from college or otherwise. The short duration made it exhausting, and my health wasn&amp;rsquo;t cooperative, especially during a 15km long trek to a 8000 ft high mountain. It was during this trek that I realized the mess my physical health was in, almost feeling like my heart would collapse. I lagged behind by about two hours, despite starting the journey together. After returning and a week of consistently sleeping 10 to 12 hours a day, the physical pain from the trip gradually subsided.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the final weeks, Professor Liebeherr organized a warm barbecue dinner for us, marking one of the best days of my entire stay. After about three months of productive work, with the support of Professor Leibeherr and my project mentor, Dixin Wu, I bid adieu to the University of Toronto with cherished memories of the lab, and field outings (for deployment of our solution).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I returned to campus for the Autumn Semester with personal milestones in mind, particularly to figure out the next path in my career. Initially, I had the idea of sitting for placements but also applying to a mix of MS and PhD programs. However, my focus in the first half of the semester shifted to gathering a third recommendation letter from my microarchitectural security project. Unfortunately, the positive results I achieved over the summer were overturned upon my return, leading me to test various hypotheses. This period was a bit disappointing as I had hoped for a publication by September. Despite this setback, I dedicated myself to the project without worrying about the outcome or my career.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Inspired by the Sulphur mountain trek, I started working out and controlling my diet. This left me lagging behind in preparing my graduate applications, and I found myself unsure whether I wanted to pursue a PhD or if an MS would suffice. Consequently, I ended up taking the GRE unplanned, only to later realize it wasn&amp;rsquo;t required for the places I applied.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After preparing a list of prospective colleges and supervisors, I began emailing them. My confidence received a boost with a few positive responses, but towards the end, I faced a struggle with the number of recommendation letters from one of my primary LoR writers. As a failsafe, I started my microspecialization project at the beginning of the semester and managed to salvage it by the semester&amp;rsquo;s end. During this time, I committed to Inter IIT, which I juggled during the semester. However, after endsems, I worried about my application and securing a good recommendation for my microspecialization thesis project, leading me to take a break from Inter IIT. I discovered a new challenge during this period—overcommitment. I was literally tired, having caught only short breaks since the Bhutan trip. Despite receiving internship opportunities from startups (yes, I am bragging), I honestly declined due to my inability to commit.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When I returned home on December 18th, I thought I finally caught a break, but then came a research project opportunity with potential graduate opportunities, and I couldn&amp;rsquo;t turn it down. Although I anticipate not fully enjoying my last semester on campus, I refrain from complaining since I feel fortunate to receive such an opportunity.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As promised, the year kept getting better in terms of career prospects, and I am grateful for that. While I realized a lot of things this year, I barely shared them with anyone. Consequently, I believe this has been the longest I haven&amp;rsquo;t complained about anything. I feel grateful for everything; at least that keeps my head light. On personal milestones, I did lose more than 17 kgs of weight, although it&amp;rsquo;s just a fraction of what I should lose. This year, instead of time, I wasted a lot of money, and I hope that won&amp;rsquo;t be the case next year. I believe the major reason this year was so delightful is because 2 + 0 + 2 + 3 equals 7 (thala for a reason).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the coming year, my primary focus will be on chasing discipline and completing my weight loss journey. I aim to seize the current opportunities and feel a tinge of sadness as I approach my last semester on campus. Reflecting on decisions that I might have initially regretted, such as choosing KGP and my branch, I am confident that looking back, I wouldn&amp;rsquo;t change a thing. Every decision, whether good or bad, has played a role in bringing me to this point in my life. The positive experiences have been truly uplifting, while the challenges and bad decisions have contributed to shaping me and making me mentally tougher. With this outlook, we move forward into 2024.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Cheers! Happy New year folks.Thanks for reading, see you soon.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Signing off &lt;br&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/adi4comp&#34;&gt;Aditya Ranjan Jha&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>I am on vacation...</title>
      <link>https://adi4blogs.netlify.app/posts/blog-entry-08/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 30 Jun 2023 05:59:27 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://adi4blogs.netlify.app/posts/blog-entry-08/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;image.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Today marks the conclusion of the first half of 2023. As I reflect on these past months, it&amp;rsquo;s clear that I&amp;rsquo;ve encountered some challenges. However, I believe that this year has not been in vain. Amidst it all, there are aspects for which I am truly grateful.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One of the bright spots has been my time in Canada. The beauty of this country surrounds me, and each day brings a sense of warmth and positivity. Additionally, I appreciate the work ethic prevalent here, which has propelled me forward. The progress I&amp;rsquo;ve made is commendable, and although my current domain may not align with my post-graduation plans, I consider myself fortunate to have exceptional supervisors who are not only training me in technical skills but also imparting knowledge about research methodology and problem-solving. This overall experience has boosted my confidence. However, there are still personal challenges I struggle to overcome.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Those who engage in discussions with me or seek my guidance often perceive me as possessing a distinct mindset with exceptional self-control. Regrettably, that perception is not entirely accurate. While I do exercise control over a significant portion of my mind, there remains a part that is untamed, comparable to an unleashed dog. My motivation to address these personal demons tends to be short-lived. If I could somehow overcome the barriers preventing me from relinquishing things I should have let go of long ago, I believe I could become a physically and mentally resilient individual. Yet, I must admit that I have been failing for a considerable time. I&amp;rsquo;m uncertain when I became so lacking in willpower. There was a period when willpower was among my most formidable traits, but now I find myself unable to rein in my dopamine-driven brain and my perpetually hungry stomach. Time is passing, and I am growing older, all while still unsure of what lies ahead in life. While my previous retrospections have demonstrated the benefits of accepting and making the best of my circumstances, there remains an underlying fear that lingers. My most recent mental accomplishment has been the realization of letting go of worries that are beyond my control, and instead focusing on maximizing what I have while refraining from complaints. This realization has served as my driving force. However, I sense that my motivation is waning, and it is crucial for me to make progress. Although I possess the intellect to identify my demons, I lack the courage to confront them. This inner conflict consumes me daily, even as I lay down to sleep, yearning for the prospect of a better tomorrow. Yet, I find myself in the same weakened state each day.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I believe that perhaps I have been trying too hard to combat my weaknesses; it is time to approach this battle wisely. Rather than implementing drastic and short-lived lifestyle changes, I should focus on making small adjustments that can be sustained. It&amp;rsquo;s true that countless individuals have extolled the effectiveness of incremental changes, but I have always been reluctant to seek advice, even though I have undoubtedly missed out on valuable insights throughout my life. Somehow, I derive satisfaction from deciphering these moral codes on my own, despite their availability to us all. Therefore, I propose dividing my objectives into two distinct tasks: identifying what needs to be relinquished and determining which habits I need to adopt. Although this endeavor aims to restore discipline, I am well aware that it will require time. Instead of hiding behind the shadows of these retrospective blog posts and merely acknowledging my flaws without taking action, I must focus on personal growth before returning to this platform to share my progress at the end of the year. In essence, I am truly going on a journey of self-improvement for the latter half of 2023, akin to a vacation dedicated to my personal well-being.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Thanks for reading, see you soon.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;PS: I asked chatgpt to make the language of my blog elegant and free from typos.
&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Signing off &lt;br&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/adi4comp&#34;&gt;Aditya Ranjan Jha&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Second Month into retrospection</title>
      <link>https://adi4blogs.netlify.app/posts/blog-entry-07/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 21 Mar 2023 08:56:18 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://adi4blogs.netlify.app/posts/blog-entry-07/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;image.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;February started with tests and midsems, I could not focus on my work because of the same although somehow I managed to go through the stressful midsem fortnite without much panic this time, although I could have studied a bit more for my electives. Other than this time I was involved in one of my project works and lost a track of time and couldn&amp;rsquo;t balance time and this time I was struck so deep into one of the projects that when I went home I couldn&amp;rsquo;t spend time with my family too. Through this, I realized a positive and negative quality of my character. The positive reinforcement was not just self-realization but was through the appreciation of the project mentors. The positive quality was me being stuck to the problem until it is resolved, thus helping me realize my only strength, hard work. The negative being struck to the problem until it is resolved, being cocky and skipping my regular routine, going absolutely off my schedule. And as I speak of this, it can be easily inferred that I still have discipline issues as stated in the previous blog.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One of these days was Holi, it was one of the dullest and most depressing days on my campus as my friends whom I am usually with, were home. I made a resolution to have some routine in my life, I was able to simulate it for slightly over a week. But again when the project I was so involved with getting over on Friday. After all the mental exhaustion, I felt the need to have a day off. I planned to study some books related to my curriculum and others but I just skipped all of that and till this time I am binge-watching suits, completely gone off track, the schedule has been disrupted and I am still not able to bring it on track.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I realized that when I am struck with some task I can give my full dedication to it, I don’t know why but I feel the need for closure and when the work is done, I lose the will to do anything else. I plan to come back on track and somehow I understand that I have to keep some time off everything so that I won’t get exhausted and when I take breaks, I don’t go rogue and regret it later. Well, this sums up the whole guilt trip, I have been having for the past 2 days, I am very ashamed but when I started this it was 2:00 pm and I started binge-watching again, and it’s 6:00 pm now. My biggest problem is I have no control even though I know my ills, when I cross that thin line rather than coming back, I go rogue and make it worse. I have always been able to realize this but never correct it. Now that I see it, I think it’s my biggest ill.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Today is also the day class X boards end and I just realized it has been 6 long years since it ended for me. I would have never thought to make it this far and certainly I feel old. It’s uptime for me to make amends to my living, I am just writing this as a log so that I never forget. There are many things to do I better start soon because soon I will be out of undergraduate too. Let’s see if I can come back after crossing boundaries or still go rogue next time I write these blogs&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>First month into retrospection</title>
      <link>https://adi4blogs.netlify.app/posts/blog-entry-06/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 11 Feb 2023 19:47:55 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://adi4blogs.netlify.app/posts/blog-entry-06/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;blog6-cover.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The year started with me going to Bhutan on the first day of the year. Probably the nicest time I will have in the whole year, although when I was on the trip I wanted to come back and resume my work and come to campus as the semester already started and I was missing the entire first week of classes. During this trip, I had a lot of time to think, relax and enjoy the trip as well. The weather was chilly but the rooms were cozy and after a whole day of exploring the places I used to love to come to my room and work. To be honest, I was not as excited as the other members on the trip, but now when I think about it, I am not going to have that level of peace and serenity for a long time.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After I came back I was excited to dwell into my work, I had 2 projects ongoing, I enjoyed being busy and at the same time, I attended classes to keep up with acads. But soon I fell ill and I don’t know how but the sickness prevailed for the next 2 to 3 weeks. During my trip to Bhutan, I made some resolutions just to increase my willpower and also improve my health which as I mentioned earlier is kind of my only resolution, this year. So I avoided sugar, maida, and junk food, ate a meal once a day, and the remaining time sprouts or milk. But it was hard to keep my mental sanity and ridiculously decrease the calorie intake, since I was ill too I became weak and had to quit after 2 weeks, My other streak was of taking a bath daily which I did at &lt;strong&gt;-3 degree&lt;/strong&gt; Celsius in Bhutan too. I recently broke this streak on 9th February due to a hectic and messed up day which I may mention ahead. After recovering from illness, I was not able to bring my dietary habits on track and thus yet to this day I am yet to come back to my resolution. During all this, I was trying to do my work and was busy with one of the works and thus also began to skip my learning time. At the end of last month, I got an offer for a summer research project, which sounds great but was a nightmare for me. I have been working in various fields all of which fall into one big domain, this one was one of them but not exactly the one I want to pursue higher studies in, so I wasn&amp;rsquo;t sure to choose between this research opportunity or my industry internship offer that I got through campus. Thus, upon considering the views of some of my seniors and friends and yes ChatGPT I made my choice. I questioned my choice for many days, seeing nightmares about the road not taken, for real used to have dreams about it. Well, I am a bit calmer now, since I talked to my professor and one of the seniors working in the industry. Well during this time fest was going on and I missed almost all of it and realized the value of having people around although on the non fest days I prefer to be in my solitude.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So I went home, met my family, and tried to bring my messed-up routine on track, but I couldn&amp;rsquo;t. Since we are retrospecting, I should be completely honest.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Since I have started working on 2 projects, I am not able to give time to learning and the thought of losing time always bothers me, whether I am in my room or outside in a gathering. I have lost discipline and concentration. So, the harder I try to force it on me, the farther it’s going away from me. I think about changes I should make to my life; then as usual I think of starting on a fresh day and the remaining time is wasted and I am not able to start the next day too. The cycle keeps on repeating and thus to compensate for the time lost I cancel the time that I should give to my health or other self-development habits or to be very honest, meal time. I know my demons and thus I am always worried and anxious about fixing them. But I can&amp;rsquo;t find a way for rather than forcing discipline into my life, it should be a part of me. I have a lot to defend and a lot to fight for, I need a way to balance both of them. Rather than waiting for the clock to sync and then make changes in my life. I should function asynchronously and reset the clock at the present time because if I don’t, I am going to miss the posedge of the next clock cycle and never going to make changes to my life. I think I may have to read the book I have been cursing my friend for reading (Atomic Habits). Also, I think I should stop making targets to complete and just do what I can.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So yeah thats it.
&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Signing off &lt;br&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/adi4comp&#34;&gt;Aditya Ranjan Jha&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Y22 Wrapped!</title>
      <link>https://adi4blogs.netlify.app/posts/blog-entry-05/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 31 Dec 2022 23:40:26 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://adi4blogs.netlify.app/posts/blog-entry-05/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;blog-cover.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So trying to sum up this year in the final hour of 2022! This year was full of ups and downs, but all in all what a happening year. I cried I laughed, I tried and I slept. This year had 3 emotions all in all: realization, denial and acceptance. The year started with a whole list of realizations and among a tough crowd. As soon as I reached campus I realized the competence of the crowd there and how relaxed I was at home, completely cut off from what was going on in people&amp;rsquo;s life and career. Not only that, I realized how much of goss, a great bunch of people, and societies I missed. Well coming to some facts, I was addicted to games back in my 3rd Semester and my learning curve stopped. I was able to escape that thing after coming to campus and interacting with real people. But I didn&amp;rsquo;t realize the latter until it was pointed out to me in 2 project selection interviews. These events shook my confidence. I didn&amp;rsquo;t know what I wanted to do. I didn&amp;rsquo;t know what domain I wanted to work in. I didn&amp;rsquo;t know how to cover the gap of one whole semester in my learning curve. When many of my friends had a lot of progress in their life in a definite direction. I was directionless. Finding work experience seemed difficult to me as I didn&amp;rsquo;t have a good academic background, I wanted to work in a field that required a lot of knowledge to begin with and I am not ok or good with bluffing (I am not street or any kind of smart). Well, this sums up the realization phase of the year.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With all these realizations, I eventually went into denial and wasted a lot of time looking back on what I lost and worrying about what I am going to lose. Well I still sometimes do the latter. I went into absolute tryhard and started losing even more. I skipped events and fest to do something,felt separated, trying to deny what can&amp;rsquo;t be undone. Well I absolutely forgot what it&amp;rsquo;s to be around people and the value of social events that I have limited counts left of. Finally after getting nothing going my way in the first half of the year, my &amp;ldquo;grand comeback&amp;rdquo; failed and  I realized my mistakes and started letting go of things eventually and as I would like to say in the lingo &amp;ldquo;Peace marna seekh gaya &amp;lsquo;&amp;rsquo;. This sums up the denial stage of my Y22.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the acceptance stage being at home helped a lot in the summer breaks and of course some friends helped too. As soon as I started letting go of things, some things started aligning themselves in the direction I wanted them too. Well, I was at a point of time when I had nothing to defend or lose. And as I have mentioned earlier, will to work is associated with a reward-based system, if you don&amp;rsquo;t get rewarded for your actions your will to move ahead stagnates. And then I was rewarded with one opportunity which helped me get confidence for other opportunities and I grabbed some of them too. So, all in all, I had a direction to move but since nothing lasts forever, neither bad times nor the good times. I was again struck, hence started performing bad academically and socially, but the good thing I was much more calm this time, didn&amp;rsquo;t panic let things go and started retrospection, and found out that I am too far from my goal and may have applied for some wrong fellowship projects, anyways nothing can be done about that and hence again I had nothing in my hand to lose or defend, so I started working and got some valuable work opportunities, but on the social front I have become much more awkward, I am out of words most of the times, it&amp;rsquo;s like I have forgotten to talk with new people. My memory has also become week, I have experienced brain freeze moment many times in past one or two months. I have lost confidence in many things including sports.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So yes, My 2022 story doesn&amp;rsquo;t end on a perfect note, but what an amazing year I had. I learned so much, I enhanced my power of retrospection, I got some amazing confidence boosting opportunities, got more clear picture of what I want to become, came closer to my family and best of all made some amazing friends along the way, who I expect are the only readers of this blog. So happy new year folks, wish you an amazing year ahead. So with me in 2023 I carry a lot of work opportunities to convert into outcome, a poor physical health which I wish to repair and kind of my only resolution, this year and hope for the end of my yips on the social front of my personality. I also wish to connect with many people who I never contacted in 2022 and they were a crucial part of my life before that.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;PS: Completing this blog from Bhutan.
&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Signing off &lt;br&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/adi4comp&#34;&gt;Aditya Ranjan Jha&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Dear Freshman year friends......</title>
      <link>https://adi4blogs.netlify.app/posts/blog-entry-04/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 29 Dec 2022 20:09:17 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://adi4blogs.netlify.app/posts/blog-entry-04/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;blog4-cover.png&#34; alt=&#34;&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I hope you are doing well. I am writing this blog to tell you something that will save you from many panic attacks in the coming days and something I wish I knew in my freshman year. Firstly you should be proud of your JEE results but not because it reflects your IQ, it reflects your hard work and perseverance. It is a very common mistake to assume that the course of your college life wrt to your batchmates is determined by your relative ranks. The day you start your college life, your JEE success becomes invalid. Though you carry with you some fundamental science and mathematics that can just be used as tools. &lt;strong&gt;So what will make the difference between you and the rest?&lt;/strong&gt; Well you see friends, the key is time, luck, hard work, and smart work. Except for luck, the other keys are in your control. For some of you, the pursuit of knowledge may be fascinating and for some of you, the pursuit of financial success may be fascinating. Whatever suits you choose wisely the path for it, don&amp;rsquo;t follow the herd and wait for everyone to start, because time is key. You should consult your seniors on how to move forward in that path or ask about what they did, but never replicate the path, rather make your own, because every individual has a different background, different capabilities, different beliefs, and most important of all, different luck. What worked for them might work for you, might not, but of course, there will be key takeaways from their journey. While choosing a domain, if you consult someone there is a question you should not miss: &amp;ldquo;Why did you choose this field?&amp;rdquo;, Also before making a decision about &lt;strong&gt;not choosing&lt;/strong&gt; a domain you should have some reasons and not do what the herd does.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;See as much as you would curse the structure of your bachelor&amp;rsquo;s curriculum, remember that a bachelor&amp;rsquo;s is about touching up all the domains so that you pick the one that interests you, even though you might have to learn things you won&amp;rsquo;t like but most of them are worth knowing. When it comes to maintaining academic performance, from most people you would get the advice that, GPA is not of much significance or just maintain a decent GPA, but you should know scoring a high GPA right now is much easier than storing it in the senior years and if you get a headstart, it will be easier for you. In fact, your GPA will be used to judge your sincerity ahead in your career, and apart from that, it is responsible for the bundle of opportunities ahead in your career. This is something I wish I knew in my freshman year :(  But note that a high GPA doesn&amp;rsquo;t guarantee success. For that, you should possess some skills required for the work you are targeting and detailed research about what goes on in that field. In your freshman year apart from scoring good marks, you must have time to explore some fields and get a clear picture of what you want to do as soon as possible. At times you will feel that you wasted time in learning something that you won&amp;rsquo;t be pursuing a career in, but remember no knowledge is ever wasted as an engineer you are expected to have an idea about everything not just ML or DSA, and trust me, if your learning curve is continuous you would not have lack of opportunities, things will align themselves to get you a good opportunity in your career sooner or later.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Among all these things remember that making friends is important, you may have a small group of friends, but they should have your back and so should you. Being isolated and trying hard may get you success in the short term but in the long term you need to be a team player. Freshman and Sophomore year is the best time to make close friends, so rather than in pursuit of overtaking your batchies try making some friends. In moments of self-doubt, it will be difficult and your friends will be there to make it easy. And the easiest way to make friends is to join societies of your interests so that there is a high probability of finding people with similar choices and beliefs. Please look for the selection dates of respective societies and keep up with their FB page so that you don&amp;rsquo;t miss important deadlines. Me and many of my friends were not active on FB and thus missed many opportunities.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There will be times when you compare yourself with a person and find your pace in life a lot slower than his/her. There are two possible scenarios in that case:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;You think that person deserves the success and appreciation he/she is getting and what are you doing in your life?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;You think that the person doesn&amp;rsquo;t deserve the success and appreciation he/she is getting and you are not getting what you deserve&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Well, you can be wrong in both of these scenarios. But if not, start working hard if you have not yet, or in the second scenario know that the world was not fair,is not fair and will never be fair. So just keep doing what you are doing, rather than wasting time ranting, complaining, or regretting just move on. At last, I would say if nothing goes right, don&amp;rsquo;t lose hope, cherrish the things you have right now.
&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Signing off &lt;br&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/adi4comp&#34;&gt;Aditya Ranjan Jha&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>PS: I am not dead</title>
      <link>https://adi4blogs.netlify.app/posts/blog-entry-03/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 19 Aug 2022 04:24:32 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://adi4blogs.netlify.app/posts/blog-entry-03/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;image02.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;til-0145-summary-last-45-days&#34;&gt;&lt;del&gt;TIL 01/45&lt;/del&gt; Summary (Last 45 days) &lt;a href=&#34;#til-0145-summary-last-45-days&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;Last 45 days have been a roller coaster ride for me. I saw some steep falls, some momentary peaks and had some very helpful realizations. After Semester 4, I had a pretty hard time coping up with the shortcomings and results of the semester,I lost my confidence and felt insecure about my career (I still feel that ;_;). Through all this time I felt helpless and drifted away from people. But my family helps me calm down. But one thing I do best is realization, a bit slow but sharp accuracy. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After realizing the hard way, that one should have a continuous learning-time curve, This summer I explored many tech domains and got a bit clarity about what I can do for next 10 years of my life and it has always been there but yet not so clear that &lt;strong&gt;R&amp;amp;D&lt;/strong&gt; is what suits me the best. Reason being that I can&amp;rsquo;t do the same thing everyday but yes I can learn something everyday and do it for some days and then start something new. I never regret (ok maybe 80% no regret) not starting early because mostly I don&amp;rsquo;t feel clueless about what 2 geeks of any other domain talk about. Still I wish I was a master of some trait, but cool.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When the summer breaks started I was willing to prepare for all the domains (SDE, finance, core, etc) for the campus internship drives to get any backup for next summer as most of them had just one prerequisite basically Competitive Programming. But I am glad I didn&amp;rsquo;t make that mistake and focussed on finding the domain suitable for me. I spent the vacation learning from MOOCS, building self projects and working on a sponsored research project. I participated in campus internship drive primarily for core electronics and R&amp;amp;D(in my field of interest). This Summer was definitely better than previous breaks.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I have/had many problems to deal with but I gained a bit of confidence in myself and was clear on some fundamentals to move ahead. Seeing people worried about CDC internship drives, some biases/preferences, some not so fair processes caused rift between many people, increased toxicity and through that I was able to see clearly that me or anyone else can&amp;rsquo;t change the process, the world is unfair we have to accept that and move ahead. I sat for some tests and 1 interview each on Day 1 and Day 2. I felt the fear of losing the day 1 chance at Google Hardware but the next day after losing Google Hardware, I was not so worried on Day 2 and got an offer from Texas Instruments. It was a long weekend but I was lucky to make it through. After that I have been looking for projects and research opportunities to work on, but I am out of ideas. I am confused again about what I should learn next ? Should I master core electronics or explore something new ? Becoz this is my last year to learn anything during undergrad (Pre-Final Year Undergrad).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The only thing I learnt from last 2 months is that, the beauty of time is that whether good or bad it passes away&amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Signing off &lt;br&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/adi4comp&#34;&gt;Aditya Ranjan Jha&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A Question, I can&#39;t Really answer right now.</title>
      <link>https://adi4blogs.netlify.app/posts/blog-entry-02/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 25 Jun 2022 01:42:34 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://adi4blogs.netlify.app/posts/blog-entry-02/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;cover.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;i-really-dont-know&#34;&gt;I really don&amp;rsquo;t know! &lt;a href=&#34;#i-really-dont-know&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;Yo! So this is it, finally I am starting to write this blog. I have been planning to write this blog since last weekend but mehhhh, I am lazy. So since last one week I have been bombed with a specific genre of questions by my well wishers:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&amp;ldquo;What next? What do I plan to do next? What profile have I shortlisted for the upcoming campus internship drive? Or do I plan to go for research?&amp;hellip;&amp;rdquo;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you had asked me the same question 3-4 months back then I would have had a clear answer for these questions, But to be honest, I have no idea right now. Last few months have been rough on me, I have been rejected for several project opportunities, performed badly in acads, brutally rejected in a project interview and was made to realize that I am not even near my research interest. Well in short I succumbed to the competition. And the results of last semester made it worse. I really lost my confidence and still feel insecure about my future.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But time heals everything and it really has helped me to realize a lot of things I have been doing wrong, I have corrected some of them, some mistakes are beyond repair and some I still can&amp;rsquo;t stop doing. But still I try to avoid the question &lt;strong&gt;What next?&lt;/strong&gt;. Since the start of summers I have been trying to shortlist a set of profiles or broaden my area of interest. But every time I sit with a notepad jotting down a set of topics that I like, the list becomes toooo long and I can&amp;rsquo;t figure &lt;strong&gt;the one&lt;/strong&gt; out of them. But earlier this week I realized these things are a compilation of  what I imagined myself to be when I am over 18 and all of those topics suddenly seemed to be a wishlist bucket. Well so the question still stands: &lt;strong&gt;What do I want to be?&lt;/strong&gt; because i don&amp;rsquo;t think I am master in any of them and it&amp;rsquo;s uptime for me to make a decision because now I am in pre-final year.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So I did what I thought was right to do, I closed my eyes and slept for straight 3 hrs. Well the picture was not clear to me. So I closed my eyes again and slept&amp;hellip;. Jk I didn&amp;rsquo;t sleep, I tried to imagine what I can work on for the next 10 years and not regret it. But tbh nothing close came to my mind, It&amp;rsquo;s just void. I can&amp;rsquo;t see my future in anything. At Least people have fantasies about the next 5 years of their life but I don&amp;rsquo;t see any of them right now. It&amp;rsquo;s Void!!.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But again the best thing I have learnt this summer is to calm down and let time fill the void. I don&amp;rsquo;t feel too tense about what I will do next, because one thing that I know for sure is it may take time but I always get a part of what I want and yes I can live with that.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;P.S. -&amp;gt; I wrote this blog so that I can calm down and always remember what I really think is a good lesson for me.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Signing off &lt;br&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/adi4comp&#34;&gt;Aditya Ranjan Jha&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Hello World!</title>
      <link>https://adi4blogs.netlify.app/posts/blog-entry-01/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 18 Jun 2022 01:44:12 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://adi4blogs.netlify.app/posts/blog-entry-01/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;mario-hi-unscreen.gif&#34; alt=&#34;&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;hello-readers-welcome-to-adiboys-blogs&#34;&gt;Hello Readers, Welcome to Adiboy&amp;rsquo;s Blogs! &lt;a href=&#34;#hello-readers-welcome-to-adiboys-blogs&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;h4 id=&#34;why-am-i-starting-to-write-blogs&#34;&gt;Why am I starting to write blogs? &lt;a href=&#34;#why-am-i-starting-to-write-blogs&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;&lt;p&gt;I always wanted to write blogs. On many nights when i go to sleep, I feel like sharing about my day with someone or maybe write a diary entry or sometimes share good memories on social media, but I dont feel comfortable doing any of that. So yeah, I guess Blogs will work.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;what-to-expect-from-my-blogs&#34;&gt;What to expect from my blogs? &lt;a href=&#34;#what-to-expect-from-my-blogs&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;&lt;p&gt;Honestly, &lt;strong&gt;Not very mesmerizing English, Not very motivational stuff, Not very relavent stuff either (atleast most of the times) or Not even very informational stuff either&lt;/strong&gt;.
But only some basic understandable writeups and something I wish I could have said to more people than i can. &lt;strong&gt;Note: Forgive me for grammatical errors and typos.&lt;/strong&gt; I will learn eventually&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;whats-next&#34;&gt;Whats next? &lt;a href=&#34;#whats-next&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;&lt;p&gt;I will try to write blog atleast thrice a week or maybe dump some memories(pics), I do want to stay busy writing blogs so I dont waste time doing random stuff. Well this maybe a big thing to commit but I do want to talk about personal finance, self realization, dump photos and maybe someday write lifestyle blogs&amp;hellip;&amp;hellip;. phrrrrwww (the last one is just something i like to say i dont know what the hell is that).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So yeah thats it.
&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Signing off &lt;br&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/adi4comp&#34;&gt;Aditya Ranjan Jha&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
