<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Retrospection on Aditya Unfiltered</title>
    <link>https://adi4blogs.netlify.app/tags/retrospection/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Retrospection on Aditya Unfiltered</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 30 Jun 2023 05:59:27 -0400</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://adi4blogs.netlify.app/tags/retrospection/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>I am on vacation...</title>
      <link>https://adi4blogs.netlify.app/posts/blog-entry-08/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 30 Jun 2023 05:59:27 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://adi4blogs.netlify.app/posts/blog-entry-08/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;image.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Today marks the conclusion of the first half of 2023. As I reflect on these past months, it&amp;rsquo;s clear that I&amp;rsquo;ve encountered some challenges. However, I believe that this year has not been in vain. Amidst it all, there are aspects for which I am truly grateful.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One of the bright spots has been my time in Canada. The beauty of this country surrounds me, and each day brings a sense of warmth and positivity. Additionally, I appreciate the work ethic prevalent here, which has propelled me forward. The progress I&amp;rsquo;ve made is commendable, and although my current domain may not align with my post-graduation plans, I consider myself fortunate to have exceptional supervisors who are not only training me in technical skills but also imparting knowledge about research methodology and problem-solving. This overall experience has boosted my confidence. However, there are still personal challenges I struggle to overcome.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Those who engage in discussions with me or seek my guidance often perceive me as possessing a distinct mindset with exceptional self-control. Regrettably, that perception is not entirely accurate. While I do exercise control over a significant portion of my mind, there remains a part that is untamed, comparable to an unleashed dog. My motivation to address these personal demons tends to be short-lived. If I could somehow overcome the barriers preventing me from relinquishing things I should have let go of long ago, I believe I could become a physically and mentally resilient individual. Yet, I must admit that I have been failing for a considerable time. I&amp;rsquo;m uncertain when I became so lacking in willpower. There was a period when willpower was among my most formidable traits, but now I find myself unable to rein in my dopamine-driven brain and my perpetually hungry stomach. Time is passing, and I am growing older, all while still unsure of what lies ahead in life. While my previous retrospections have demonstrated the benefits of accepting and making the best of my circumstances, there remains an underlying fear that lingers. My most recent mental accomplishment has been the realization of letting go of worries that are beyond my control, and instead focusing on maximizing what I have while refraining from complaints. This realization has served as my driving force. However, I sense that my motivation is waning, and it is crucial for me to make progress. Although I possess the intellect to identify my demons, I lack the courage to confront them. This inner conflict consumes me daily, even as I lay down to sleep, yearning for the prospect of a better tomorrow. Yet, I find myself in the same weakened state each day.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I believe that perhaps I have been trying too hard to combat my weaknesses; it is time to approach this battle wisely. Rather than implementing drastic and short-lived lifestyle changes, I should focus on making small adjustments that can be sustained. It&amp;rsquo;s true that countless individuals have extolled the effectiveness of incremental changes, but I have always been reluctant to seek advice, even though I have undoubtedly missed out on valuable insights throughout my life. Somehow, I derive satisfaction from deciphering these moral codes on my own, despite their availability to us all. Therefore, I propose dividing my objectives into two distinct tasks: identifying what needs to be relinquished and determining which habits I need to adopt. Although this endeavor aims to restore discipline, I am well aware that it will require time. Instead of hiding behind the shadows of these retrospective blog posts and merely acknowledging my flaws without taking action, I must focus on personal growth before returning to this platform to share my progress at the end of the year. In essence, I am truly going on a journey of self-improvement for the latter half of 2023, akin to a vacation dedicated to my personal well-being.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Thanks for reading, see you soon.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;PS: I asked chatgpt to make the language of my blog elegant and free from typos.
&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Signing off &lt;br&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/adi4comp&#34;&gt;Aditya Ranjan Jha&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Second Month into retrospection</title>
      <link>https://adi4blogs.netlify.app/posts/blog-entry-07/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 21 Mar 2023 08:56:18 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://adi4blogs.netlify.app/posts/blog-entry-07/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;image.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;February started with tests and midsems, I could not focus on my work because of the same although somehow I managed to go through the stressful midsem fortnite without much panic this time, although I could have studied a bit more for my electives. Other than this time I was involved in one of my project works and lost a track of time and couldn&amp;rsquo;t balance time and this time I was struck so deep into one of the projects that when I went home I couldn&amp;rsquo;t spend time with my family too. Through this, I realized a positive and negative quality of my character. The positive reinforcement was not just self-realization but was through the appreciation of the project mentors. The positive quality was me being stuck to the problem until it is resolved, thus helping me realize my only strength, hard work. The negative being struck to the problem until it is resolved, being cocky and skipping my regular routine, going absolutely off my schedule. And as I speak of this, it can be easily inferred that I still have discipline issues as stated in the previous blog.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One of these days was Holi, it was one of the dullest and most depressing days on my campus as my friends whom I am usually with, were home. I made a resolution to have some routine in my life, I was able to simulate it for slightly over a week. But again when the project I was so involved with getting over on Friday. After all the mental exhaustion, I felt the need to have a day off. I planned to study some books related to my curriculum and others but I just skipped all of that and till this time I am binge-watching suits, completely gone off track, the schedule has been disrupted and I am still not able to bring it on track.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I realized that when I am struck with some task I can give my full dedication to it, I don’t know why but I feel the need for closure and when the work is done, I lose the will to do anything else. I plan to come back on track and somehow I understand that I have to keep some time off everything so that I won’t get exhausted and when I take breaks, I don’t go rogue and regret it later. Well, this sums up the whole guilt trip, I have been having for the past 2 days, I am very ashamed but when I started this it was 2:00 pm and I started binge-watching again, and it’s 6:00 pm now. My biggest problem is I have no control even though I know my ills, when I cross that thin line rather than coming back, I go rogue and make it worse. I have always been able to realize this but never correct it. Now that I see it, I think it’s my biggest ill.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Today is also the day class X boards end and I just realized it has been 6 long years since it ended for me. I would have never thought to make it this far and certainly I feel old. It’s uptime for me to make amends to my living, I am just writing this as a log so that I never forget. There are many things to do I better start soon because soon I will be out of undergraduate too. Let’s see if I can come back after crossing boundaries or still go rogue next time I write these blogs&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>First month into retrospection</title>
      <link>https://adi4blogs.netlify.app/posts/blog-entry-06/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 11 Feb 2023 19:47:55 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://adi4blogs.netlify.app/posts/blog-entry-06/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;blog6-cover.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The year started with me going to Bhutan on the first day of the year. Probably the nicest time I will have in the whole year, although when I was on the trip I wanted to come back and resume my work and come to campus as the semester already started and I was missing the entire first week of classes. During this trip, I had a lot of time to think, relax and enjoy the trip as well. The weather was chilly but the rooms were cozy and after a whole day of exploring the places I used to love to come to my room and work. To be honest, I was not as excited as the other members on the trip, but now when I think about it, I am not going to have that level of peace and serenity for a long time.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After I came back I was excited to dwell into my work, I had 2 projects ongoing, I enjoyed being busy and at the same time, I attended classes to keep up with acads. But soon I fell ill and I don’t know how but the sickness prevailed for the next 2 to 3 weeks. During my trip to Bhutan, I made some resolutions just to increase my willpower and also improve my health which as I mentioned earlier is kind of my only resolution, this year. So I avoided sugar, maida, and junk food, ate a meal once a day, and the remaining time sprouts or milk. But it was hard to keep my mental sanity and ridiculously decrease the calorie intake, since I was ill too I became weak and had to quit after 2 weeks, My other streak was of taking a bath daily which I did at &lt;strong&gt;-3 degree&lt;/strong&gt; Celsius in Bhutan too. I recently broke this streak on 9th February due to a hectic and messed up day which I may mention ahead. After recovering from illness, I was not able to bring my dietary habits on track and thus yet to this day I am yet to come back to my resolution. During all this, I was trying to do my work and was busy with one of the works and thus also began to skip my learning time. At the end of last month, I got an offer for a summer research project, which sounds great but was a nightmare for me. I have been working in various fields all of which fall into one big domain, this one was one of them but not exactly the one I want to pursue higher studies in, so I wasn&amp;rsquo;t sure to choose between this research opportunity or my industry internship offer that I got through campus. Thus, upon considering the views of some of my seniors and friends and yes ChatGPT I made my choice. I questioned my choice for many days, seeing nightmares about the road not taken, for real used to have dreams about it. Well, I am a bit calmer now, since I talked to my professor and one of the seniors working in the industry. Well during this time fest was going on and I missed almost all of it and realized the value of having people around although on the non fest days I prefer to be in my solitude.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So I went home, met my family, and tried to bring my messed-up routine on track, but I couldn&amp;rsquo;t. Since we are retrospecting, I should be completely honest.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Since I have started working on 2 projects, I am not able to give time to learning and the thought of losing time always bothers me, whether I am in my room or outside in a gathering. I have lost discipline and concentration. So, the harder I try to force it on me, the farther it’s going away from me. I think about changes I should make to my life; then as usual I think of starting on a fresh day and the remaining time is wasted and I am not able to start the next day too. The cycle keeps on repeating and thus to compensate for the time lost I cancel the time that I should give to my health or other self-development habits or to be very honest, meal time. I know my demons and thus I am always worried and anxious about fixing them. But I can&amp;rsquo;t find a way for rather than forcing discipline into my life, it should be a part of me. I have a lot to defend and a lot to fight for, I need a way to balance both of them. Rather than waiting for the clock to sync and then make changes in my life. I should function asynchronously and reset the clock at the present time because if I don’t, I am going to miss the posedge of the next clock cycle and never going to make changes to my life. I think I may have to read the book I have been cursing my friend for reading (Atomic Habits). Also, I think I should stop making targets to complete and just do what I can.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So yeah thats it.
&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Signing off &lt;br&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/adi4comp&#34;&gt;Aditya Ranjan Jha&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A Question, I can&#39;t Really answer right now.</title>
      <link>https://adi4blogs.netlify.app/posts/blog-entry-02/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 25 Jun 2022 01:42:34 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://adi4blogs.netlify.app/posts/blog-entry-02/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;cover.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;i-really-dont-know&#34;&gt;I really don&amp;rsquo;t know! &lt;a href=&#34;#i-really-dont-know&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;Yo! So this is it, finally I am starting to write this blog. I have been planning to write this blog since last weekend but mehhhh, I am lazy. So since last one week I have been bombed with a specific genre of questions by my well wishers:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&amp;ldquo;What next? What do I plan to do next? What profile have I shortlisted for the upcoming campus internship drive? Or do I plan to go for research?&amp;hellip;&amp;rdquo;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you had asked me the same question 3-4 months back then I would have had a clear answer for these questions, But to be honest, I have no idea right now. Last few months have been rough on me, I have been rejected for several project opportunities, performed badly in acads, brutally rejected in a project interview and was made to realize that I am not even near my research interest. Well in short I succumbed to the competition. And the results of last semester made it worse. I really lost my confidence and still feel insecure about my future.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But time heals everything and it really has helped me to realize a lot of things I have been doing wrong, I have corrected some of them, some mistakes are beyond repair and some I still can&amp;rsquo;t stop doing. But still I try to avoid the question &lt;strong&gt;What next?&lt;/strong&gt;. Since the start of summers I have been trying to shortlist a set of profiles or broaden my area of interest. But every time I sit with a notepad jotting down a set of topics that I like, the list becomes toooo long and I can&amp;rsquo;t figure &lt;strong&gt;the one&lt;/strong&gt; out of them. But earlier this week I realized these things are a compilation of  what I imagined myself to be when I am over 18 and all of those topics suddenly seemed to be a wishlist bucket. Well so the question still stands: &lt;strong&gt;What do I want to be?&lt;/strong&gt; because i don&amp;rsquo;t think I am master in any of them and it&amp;rsquo;s uptime for me to make a decision because now I am in pre-final year.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So I did what I thought was right to do, I closed my eyes and slept for straight 3 hrs. Well the picture was not clear to me. So I closed my eyes again and slept&amp;hellip;. Jk I didn&amp;rsquo;t sleep, I tried to imagine what I can work on for the next 10 years and not regret it. But tbh nothing close came to my mind, It&amp;rsquo;s just void. I can&amp;rsquo;t see my future in anything. At Least people have fantasies about the next 5 years of their life but I don&amp;rsquo;t see any of them right now. It&amp;rsquo;s Void!!.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But again the best thing I have learnt this summer is to calm down and let time fill the void. I don&amp;rsquo;t feel too tense about what I will do next, because one thing that I know for sure is it may take time but I always get a part of what I want and yes I can live with that.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;P.S. -&amp;gt; I wrote this blog so that I can calm down and always remember what I really think is a good lesson for me.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Signing off &lt;br&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/adi4comp&#34;&gt;Aditya Ranjan Jha&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
