<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Posts on Adiboy Blogs</title>
    
    
    
    <link>https://adi4blogs.netlify.app/posts/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Posts on Adiboy Blogs</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 11 Feb 2023 19:47:55 +0530</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://adi4blogs.netlify.app/posts/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>First month into retrospection</title>
      <link>https://adi4blogs.netlify.app/posts/blog-entry-06/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 11 Feb 2023 19:47:55 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://adi4blogs.netlify.app/posts/blog-entry-06/</guid>
      <description>
        
          &lt;img src=&#34;https://adi4blogs.netlify.app/posts/blog-entry-06/blog6-cover.jpg&#34;/&gt;
          
        
        
        
          The year started with me going to Bhutan on the first day of the year. Probably the nicest time I will have in the whole year, although when I was on the trip I wanted to come back and resume my work and come to campus as the semester already started and I was missing the entire first week of classes. During this trip, I had a lot of time to think, relax and enjoy the trip as well.
          
        
        </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Y22 Wrapped!</title>
      <link>https://adi4blogs.netlify.app/posts/blog-entry-05/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 31 Dec 2022 23:40:26 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://adi4blogs.netlify.app/posts/blog-entry-05/</guid>
      <description>
        
          &lt;img src=&#34;https://adi4blogs.netlify.app/posts/blog-entry-05/blog-cover.jpg&#34;/&gt;
          
        
        
        
          So trying to sum up this year in the final hour of 2022! This year was full of ups and downs, but all in all what a happening year. I cried I laughed, I tried and I slept. This year had 3 emotions all in all: realization, denial and acceptance. The year started with a whole list of realizations and among a tough crowd. As soon as I reached campus I realized the competence of the crowd there and how relaxed I was at home, completely cut off from what was going on in people&amp;rsquo;s life and career.
          
        
        </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Dear Freshman year friends......</title>
      <link>https://adi4blogs.netlify.app/posts/blog-entry-04/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 29 Dec 2022 20:09:17 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://adi4blogs.netlify.app/posts/blog-entry-04/</guid>
      <description>
        
          &lt;img src=&#34;https://adi4blogs.netlify.app/posts/blog-entry-04/blog4-cover.png&#34;/&gt;
          
        
        
        
          I hope you are doing well. I am writing this blog to tell you something that will save you from many panic attacks in the coming days and something I wish I knew in my freshman year. Firstly you should be proud of your JEE results but not because it reflects your IQ, it reflects your hard work and perseverance. It is a very common mistake to assume that the course of your college life wrt to your batchmates is determined by your relative ranks.
          
        
        </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>PS: I am not dead</title>
      <link>https://adi4blogs.netlify.app/posts/blog-entry-03/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 19 Aug 2022 04:24:32 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://adi4blogs.netlify.app/posts/blog-entry-03/</guid>
      <description>
        
          &lt;img src=&#34;https://adi4blogs.netlify.app/posts/blog-entry-03/image02.jpg&#34;/&gt;
          
        
        
        
          TIL 01/45 Summary (Last 45 days)#Last 45 days have been a roller coaster ride for me. I saw some steep falls, some momentary peaks and had some very helpful realizations. After Semester 4, I had a pretty hard time coping up with the shortcomings and results of the semester,I lost my confidence and felt insecure about my career (I still feel that ;_;). Through all this time I felt helpless and drifted away from people.
          
        
        </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A Question, I can&#39;t Really answer right now.</title>
      <link>https://adi4blogs.netlify.app/posts/blog-entry-02/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 25 Jun 2022 01:42:34 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://adi4blogs.netlify.app/posts/blog-entry-02/</guid>
      <description>
        
          &lt;img src=&#34;https://adi4blogs.netlify.app/posts/blog-entry-02/cover.jpg&#34;/&gt;
          
        
        
        
          I really don&amp;rsquo;t know!#Yo! So this is it, finally I am starting to write this blog. I have been planning to write this blog since last weekend but mehhhh, I am lazy. So since last one week I have been bombed with a specific genre of questions by my well wishers:
&amp;ldquo;What next? What do I plan to do next? What profile have I shortlisted for the upcoming campus internship drive?
          
        
        </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Hello World!</title>
      <link>https://adi4blogs.netlify.app/posts/blog-entry-01/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 18 Jun 2022 01:44:12 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://adi4blogs.netlify.app/posts/blog-entry-01/</guid>
      <description>
        
          &lt;img src=&#34;https://adi4blogs.netlify.app/posts/blog-entry-01/mario-hi-unscreen.gif&#34;/&gt;
          
        
        
        
          Hello Readers, Welcome to Adiboy&amp;rsquo;s Blogs!#Why am I starting to write blogs?#I always wanted to write blogs. On many nights when i go to sleep, I feel like sharing about my day with someone or maybe write a diary entry or sometimes share good memories on social media, but I dont feel comfortable doing any of that. So yeah, I guess Blogs will work.
What to expect from my blogs?
          
        
        </description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>