<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>TIL on Aditya Unfiltered</title>
    <link>https://adi4blogs.netlify.app/categories/til/</link>
    <description>Recent content in TIL on Aditya Unfiltered</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 27 Oct 2024 23:33:27 +0800</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://adi4blogs.netlify.app/categories/til/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Time</title>
      <link>https://adi4blogs.netlify.app/posts/blog-entry-17/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 27 Oct 2024 23:33:27 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://adi4blogs.netlify.app/posts/blog-entry-17/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;image.png&#34; alt=&#34;&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I thought about writing a technical blog, but the illusion of having too much work this week stopped me from using my time wisely. Let&amp;rsquo;s talk about that.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We often feel overwhelmed by our workload. When we finish a task, we think we deserve a break. Yet, even if the workload isn&amp;rsquo;t that heavy and we have plenty of time left, we still feel mentally exhausted. The brain works in funny ways!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When you have a lot on your plate, your mind races with everything you want to do when you have free time. But for me, any free time I have (the kind I&amp;rsquo;m not tracking) passes by quickly. Isn&amp;rsquo;t it interesting how the semantics of time work? Time flies when you&amp;rsquo;re not thinking about it. But the moment you start to pay attention, it feels like it slows down. For example, I can hear my heartbeat when running, but my eyes are glued to the treadmill timer. I&amp;rsquo;m just waiting for those 20 minutes to pass, and it feels like I&amp;rsquo;ve run a marathon!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now, considering time as a dimension, general relativity tells us that time dilation occurs when moving at high speeds or being in a strong gravitational field. This is indeed a correct application of the theory. But is that all there is to it? Are there other factors influencing time dilation?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In physics, there&amp;rsquo;s a concept called entropy, which helps us understand how energy spreads out and becomes less useful over time. This idea can be thought of as the &amp;ldquo;arrow of time&amp;rdquo;—as things move from order to disorder. You could say time helps determine how energy is used or wasted, even if time itself isn&amp;rsquo;t consumed.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There&amp;rsquo;s also the philosophical idea of eternalism, which suggests that past, present, and future all exist at once. So, rather than time &amp;ldquo;running out,&amp;rdquo; every moment is just there, and our experience of moving through time is like traveling through a library of moments that are already written. When we feel like we&amp;rsquo;re wasting time, it might just be our perception of moving through those moments.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In a similar vein, when we think about information, time can relate to how quickly we process and understand things. If we spend time on something unproductive, it might feel like we&amp;rsquo;re wasting it—kind of like when our devices slow down, and it takes forever to get anything done.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In quantum mechanics, there’s this idea called decoherence, where the tiny building blocks of reality interact with their surroundings, making things more predictable over time. It’s a bit like how a lively party turns into a quieter gathering as people leave; the chaos settles into order.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As I explore these ideas, I wonder if any of this is true. It’s hard to grasp, right? If time exists as a dimension, what about the rate at which it changes? If all moments in time are out there, does that mean the energy at any moment never really moves on?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The uncertainty of it all makes me skeptical. Each theory presents a compelling story, but they also raise more questions than answers. If time is an illusion, what is the reality we’re experiencing? And if our perception is merely a reflection of those timelines, can we ever truly waste it? But if we stop worrying about how much time we have or don&amp;rsquo;t have, we might find that there’s enough time for everything that truly matters.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Signing off,&lt;br&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/adi4comp&#34;&gt;Aditya Ranjan Jha&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Science of Writing Science</title>
      <link>https://adi4blogs.netlify.app/posts/blog-entry-16/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 20 Oct 2024 22:38:37 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://adi4blogs.netlify.app/posts/blog-entry-16/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;image.png&#34; alt=&#34;&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This week I learned something that feels like a superpower. It’s not easy to learn, and I don’t think there&amp;rsquo;s a course for it, but it’s one of those things that, once you realize, changes how you think forever. So, buckle up—this is the introduction to some very formal lessons coming up soon.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I spent this week writing for my project, and every time I sent a draft to my advisor, I thought I’d nailed it. I mean, &lt;em&gt;masterpiece&lt;/em&gt; level nailed it. I had heard my advisor was strict about scientific communication, and I’d seen how clear his course presentations were. But when I got his feedback&amp;hellip; well, it was the same feedback everyone in the lab seemed to get. The moment I understood his point, I was both fascinated by his insight and completely embarrassed by my writing. After three rounds of edits and about a week of back-and-forth, I finally wrote&amp;hellip; &lt;em&gt;drumroll&lt;/em&gt;&amp;hellip; two pages. Yes, two whole pages! But trust me, the mistakes and the process were invaluable lessons.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;the-reality-check-my-writing-was-not-good&#34;&gt;The Reality Check: My Writing Was… Not Good &lt;a href=&#34;#the-reality-check-my-writing-was-not-good&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;First off, I had this grand illusion that my thoughts were clear and my writing was top-notch. Yeah, no. That glass has shattered. What I thought was clarity was, in reality, a confusing mess. I realize now that this probably goes back to childhood habits. I was always a messy presenter of ideas—especially in handwritten work. I hated it so much that, as a teenager, I rarely even did my own projects. I’d ask my mom or sister to make them for me! I thought those assignments were about creativity or art. But in reality, they were teaching us how to present ideas in an organized, visual way. There are people who write answers by highlighting the key points first. And then there’s me, crafting sentences so &amp;ldquo;elegant&amp;rdquo; that the point gets lost entirely.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Thinking back, I can see why my university grades sometimes looked like crash test dummies. It wasn’t just my handwriting; my ideas were stuck in my brain and didn’t make it onto the paper. Twice, I even had professors on the verge of ripping up my answer sheets! At the time, I thought it was just about presentation or handwriting, but really, the problem was that I hadn’t written down what was actually in my head.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So, here I am, finally realizing I need to fix this. Better late than never, right? From now on, I’m making an effort to get better at scientific writing. I’m going to use my blog to convey ideas, and I’ll start sending drafts to people for feedback. I’ve learned that the core of scientific writing isn’t about showing off vocabulary (sorry, past me), but about getting ideas across clearly and directly.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;keep-it-simple-and-visual&#34;&gt;Keep It Simple (And Visual!) &lt;a href=&#34;#keep-it-simple-and-visual&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;The first rule of &lt;del&gt;fight&lt;/del&gt; write club? Keep sentences short. (If this blog seems ironic to you, well, just know I’m still learning!) Long sentences lose the reader, and that makes total sense. Another key? Write in order. The best texts allow the reader to build context by reading each line in sequence, without jumping all over the place. And, surprise surprise, the simpler the writing, the better. If someone with no background can understand your work, you&amp;rsquo;ve won. Unlike literary devices, where complexity might add depth, in science, it adds confusion. The best ideas should pop up right in the beginning, so the reader doesn’t get lost in unnecessary details.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Another thing I’ve learned is about maintaining context size—each word should be an abstraction of either a well-known concept or something from your own contribution. The fewer abstractions (verbs, nouns) you use to explain your idea, the clearer it becomes. Think of it like this: it’s all about how many key words you need to describe your idea accurately. And diagrams? They’re golden. A picture really does speak a thousand words—if it’s simple enough! Diagrams should communicate ideas as cleanly and minimally as possible. If you can follow all of this, wrap things up with a strong claim to leave an impression.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here’s the cool part: I now appreciate all the things I used to overlook. Diagrams in scientific texts, animations in videos, slides in presentations—each word spoken by a presenter has a purpose. It’s so difficult to encapsulate a whole idea in just a few minutes of talking or writing. And it’s not just short presentations—long ones are hard too, because people are more likely to zone out. The challenge is to keep their attention and communicate the core idea early.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Since joining this program, I’ve seen some excellent presentations. What stood out to me was how much time these presenters spent setting up the background. Only about 25% of the time was devoted to their actual contribution. This is exactly opposite of what our bachelor thesis presentations at KGP trained us for: spend most of the time on the results! I think the focus on results was about proving our sincerity, not the novelty of our ideas (especially since we only had 10 minutes to present).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So, yeah, this blog may not fully follow the lessons I’ve learned this week, but it’s a start. I’ll be writing more technical blogs from here on out, putting these new skills into practice. Stay tuned!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Signing off,&lt;br&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/adi4comp&#34;&gt;Aditya Ranjan Jha&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
