<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Something-to-Think-About on Aditya Unfiltered</title>
    <link>https://adi4blogs.netlify.app/tags/something-to-think-about/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Something-to-Think-About on Aditya Unfiltered</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 27 Oct 2024 23:33:27 +0800</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://adi4blogs.netlify.app/tags/something-to-think-about/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Time</title>
      <link>https://adi4blogs.netlify.app/posts/blog-entry-17/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 27 Oct 2024 23:33:27 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://adi4blogs.netlify.app/posts/blog-entry-17/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;image.png&#34; alt=&#34;&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I thought about writing a technical blog, but the illusion of having too much work this week stopped me from using my time wisely. Let&amp;rsquo;s talk about that.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We often feel overwhelmed by our workload. When we finish a task, we think we deserve a break. Yet, even if the workload isn&amp;rsquo;t that heavy and we have plenty of time left, we still feel mentally exhausted. The brain works in funny ways!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When you have a lot on your plate, your mind races with everything you want to do when you have free time. But for me, any free time I have (the kind I&amp;rsquo;m not tracking) passes by quickly. Isn&amp;rsquo;t it interesting how the semantics of time work? Time flies when you&amp;rsquo;re not thinking about it. But the moment you start to pay attention, it feels like it slows down. For example, I can hear my heartbeat when running, but my eyes are glued to the treadmill timer. I&amp;rsquo;m just waiting for those 20 minutes to pass, and it feels like I&amp;rsquo;ve run a marathon!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now, considering time as a dimension, general relativity tells us that time dilation occurs when moving at high speeds or being in a strong gravitational field. This is indeed a correct application of the theory. But is that all there is to it? Are there other factors influencing time dilation?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In physics, there&amp;rsquo;s a concept called entropy, which helps us understand how energy spreads out and becomes less useful over time. This idea can be thought of as the &amp;ldquo;arrow of time&amp;rdquo;—as things move from order to disorder. You could say time helps determine how energy is used or wasted, even if time itself isn&amp;rsquo;t consumed.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There&amp;rsquo;s also the philosophical idea of eternalism, which suggests that past, present, and future all exist at once. So, rather than time &amp;ldquo;running out,&amp;rdquo; every moment is just there, and our experience of moving through time is like traveling through a library of moments that are already written. When we feel like we&amp;rsquo;re wasting time, it might just be our perception of moving through those moments.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In a similar vein, when we think about information, time can relate to how quickly we process and understand things. If we spend time on something unproductive, it might feel like we&amp;rsquo;re wasting it—kind of like when our devices slow down, and it takes forever to get anything done.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In quantum mechanics, there’s this idea called decoherence, where the tiny building blocks of reality interact with their surroundings, making things more predictable over time. It’s a bit like how a lively party turns into a quieter gathering as people leave; the chaos settles into order.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As I explore these ideas, I wonder if any of this is true. It’s hard to grasp, right? If time exists as a dimension, what about the rate at which it changes? If all moments in time are out there, does that mean the energy at any moment never really moves on?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The uncertainty of it all makes me skeptical. Each theory presents a compelling story, but they also raise more questions than answers. If time is an illusion, what is the reality we’re experiencing? And if our perception is merely a reflection of those timelines, can we ever truly waste it? But if we stop worrying about how much time we have or don&amp;rsquo;t have, we might find that there’s enough time for everything that truly matters.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Signing off,&lt;br&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/adi4comp&#34;&gt;Aditya Ranjan Jha&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
