<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>life-update on Adiboy Blogs</title>
    <link>https://adi4blogs.netlify.app/categories/life-update/</link>
    <description>Recent content in life-update on Adiboy Blogs</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 30 Jun 2023 05:59:27 -0400</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://adi4blogs.netlify.app/categories/life-update/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>I am on vacation...</title>
      <link>https://adi4blogs.netlify.app/posts/blog-entry-08/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 30 Jun 2023 05:59:27 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://adi4blogs.netlify.app/posts/blog-entry-08/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;image.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Today marks the conclusion of the first half of 2023. As I reflect on these past months, it&amp;rsquo;s clear that I&amp;rsquo;ve encountered some challenges. However, I believe that this year has not been in vain. Amidst it all, there are aspects for which I am truly grateful.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One of the bright spots has been my time in Canada. The beauty of this country surrounds me, and each day brings a sense of warmth and positivity. Additionally, I appreciate the work ethic prevalent here, which has propelled me forward. The progress I&amp;rsquo;ve made is commendable, and although my current domain may not align with my post-graduation plans, I consider myself fortunate to have exceptional supervisors who are not only training me in technical skills but also imparting knowledge about research methodology and problem-solving. This overall experience has boosted my confidence. However, there are still personal challenges I struggle to overcome.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Those who engage in discussions with me or seek my guidance often perceive me as possessing a distinct mindset with exceptional self-control. Regrettably, that perception is not entirely accurate. While I do exercise control over a significant portion of my mind, there remains a part that is untamed, comparable to an unleashed dog. My motivation to address these personal demons tends to be short-lived. If I could somehow overcome the barriers preventing me from relinquishing things I should have let go of long ago, I believe I could become a physically and mentally resilient individual. Yet, I must admit that I have been failing for a considerable time. I&amp;rsquo;m uncertain when I became so lacking in willpower. There was a period when willpower was among my most formidable traits, but now I find myself unable to rein in my dopamine-driven brain and my perpetually hungry stomach. Time is passing, and I am growing older, all while still unsure of what lies ahead in life. While my previous retrospections have demonstrated the benefits of accepting and making the best of my circumstances, there remains an underlying fear that lingers. My most recent mental accomplishment has been the realization of letting go of worries that are beyond my control, and instead focusing on maximizing what I have while refraining from complaints. This realization has served as my driving force. However, I sense that my motivation is waning, and it is crucial for me to make progress. Although I possess the intellect to identify my demons, I lack the courage to confront them. This inner conflict consumes me daily, even as I lay down to sleep, yearning for the prospect of a better tomorrow. Yet, I find myself in the same weakened state each day.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I believe that perhaps I have been trying too hard to combat my weaknesses; it is time to approach this battle wisely. Rather than implementing drastic and short-lived lifestyle changes, I should focus on making small adjustments that can be sustained. It&amp;rsquo;s true that countless individuals have extolled the effectiveness of incremental changes, but I have always been reluctant to seek advice, even though I have undoubtedly missed out on valuable insights throughout my life. Somehow, I derive satisfaction from deciphering these moral codes on my own, despite their availability to us all. Therefore, I propose dividing my objectives into two distinct tasks: identifying what needs to be relinquished and determining which habits I need to adopt. Although this endeavor aims to restore discipline, I am well aware that it will require time. Instead of hiding behind the shadows of these retrospective blog posts and merely acknowledging my flaws without taking action, I must focus on personal growth before returning to this platform to share my progress at the end of the year. In essence, I am truly going on a journey of self-improvement for the latter half of 2023, akin to a vacation dedicated to my personal well-being.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Thanks for reading, see you soon.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;PS: I asked chatgpt to make the language of my blog elegant and free from typos.
&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Signing off &lt;br&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/Adiboy3112&#34;&gt;Aditya Ranjan Jha&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Y22 Wrapped!</title>
      <link>https://adi4blogs.netlify.app/posts/blog-entry-05/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 31 Dec 2022 23:40:26 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://adi4blogs.netlify.app/posts/blog-entry-05/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;blog-cover.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So trying to sum up this year in the final hour of 2022! This year was full of ups and downs, but all in all what a happening year. I cried I laughed, I tried and I slept. This year had 3 emotions all in all: realization, denial and acceptance. The year started with a whole list of realizations and among a tough crowd. As soon as I reached campus I realized the competence of the crowd there and how relaxed I was at home, completely cut off from what was going on in people&amp;rsquo;s life and career. Not only that, I realized how much of goss, a great bunch of people, and societies I missed. Well coming to some facts, I was addicted to games back in my 3rd Semester and my learning curve stopped. I was able to escape that thing after coming to campus and interacting with real people. But I didn&amp;rsquo;t realize the latter until it was pointed out to me in 2 project selection interviews. These events shook my confidence. I didn&amp;rsquo;t know what I wanted to do. I didn&amp;rsquo;t know what domain I wanted to work in. I didn&amp;rsquo;t know how to cover the gap of one whole semester in my learning curve. When many of my friends had a lot of progress in their life in a definite direction. I was directionless. Finding work experience seemed difficult to me as I didn&amp;rsquo;t have a good academic background, I wanted to work in a field that required a lot of knowledge to begin with and I am not ok or good with bluffing (I am not street or any kind of smart). Well, this sums up the realization phase of the year.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With all these realizations, I eventually went into denial and wasted a lot of time looking back on what I lost and worrying about what I am going to lose. Well I still sometimes do the latter. I went into absolute tryhard and started losing even more. I skipped events and fest to do something,felt separated, trying to deny what can&amp;rsquo;t be undone. Well I absolutely forgot what it&amp;rsquo;s to be around people and the value of social events that I have limited counts left of. Finally after getting nothing going my way in the first half of the year, my &amp;ldquo;grand comeback&amp;rdquo; failed and  I realized my mistakes and started letting go of things eventually and as I would like to say in the lingo &amp;ldquo;Peace marna seekh gaya &amp;lsquo;&amp;rsquo;. This sums up the denial stage of my Y22.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the acceptance stage being at home helped a lot in the summer breaks and of course some friends helped too. As soon as I started letting go of things, some things started aligning themselves in the direction I wanted them too. Well, I was at a point of time when I had nothing to defend or lose. And as I have mentioned earlier, will to work is associated with a reward-based system, if you don&amp;rsquo;t get rewarded for your actions your will to move ahead stagnates. And then I was rewarded with one opportunity which helped me get confidence for other opportunities and I grabbed some of them too. So, all in all, I had a direction to move but since nothing lasts forever, neither bad times nor the good times. I was again struck, hence started performing bad academically and socially, but the good thing I was much more calm this time, didn&amp;rsquo;t panic let things go and started retrospection, and found out that I am too far from my goal and may have applied for some wrong fellowship projects, anyways nothing can be done about that and hence again I had nothing in my hand to lose or defend, so I started working and got some valuable work opportunities, but on the social front I have become much more awkward, I am out of words most of the times, it&amp;rsquo;s like I have forgotten to talk with new people. My memory has also become week, I have experienced brain freeze moment many times in past one or two months. I have lost confidence in many things including sports.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So yes, My 2022 story doesn&amp;rsquo;t end on a perfect note, but what an amazing year I had. I learned so much, I enhanced my power of retrospection, I got some amazing confidence boosting opportunities, got more clear picture of what I want to become, came closer to my family and best of all made some amazing friends along the way, who I expect are the only readers of this blog. So happy new year folks, wish you an amazing year ahead. So with me in 2023 I carry a lot of work opportunities to convert into outcome, a poor physical health which I wish to repair and kind of my only resolution, this year and hope for the end of my yips on the social front of my personality. I also wish to connect with many people who I never contacted in 2022 and they were a crucial part of my life before that.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;PS: Completing this blog from Bhutan.
&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Signing off &lt;br&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/Adiboy3112&#34;&gt;Aditya Ranjan Jha&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>PS: I am not dead</title>
      <link>https://adi4blogs.netlify.app/posts/blog-entry-03/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 19 Aug 2022 04:24:32 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://adi4blogs.netlify.app/posts/blog-entry-03/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;image02.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;til-0145-summary-last-45-days&#34;&gt;&lt;del&gt;TIL 01/45&lt;/del&gt; Summary (Last 45 days) &lt;a href=&#34;#til-0145-summary-last-45-days&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;🔗&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;Last 45 days have been a roller coaster ride for me. I saw some steep falls, some momentary peaks and had some very helpful realizations. After Semester 4, I had a pretty hard time coping up with the shortcomings and results of the semester,I lost my confidence and felt insecure about my career (I still feel that ;_;). Through all this time I felt helpless and drifted away from people. But my family helps me calm down. But one thing I do best is realization, a bit slow but sharp accuracy. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After realizing the hard way, that one should have a continuous learning-time curve, This summer I explored many tech domains and got a bit clarity about what I can do for next 10 years of my life and it has always been there but yet not so clear that &lt;strong&gt;R&amp;amp;D&lt;/strong&gt; is what suits me the best. Reason being that I can&amp;rsquo;t do the same thing everyday but yes I can learn something everyday and do it for some days and then start something new. I never regret (ok maybe 80% no regret) not starting early because mostly I don&amp;rsquo;t feel clueless about what 2 geeks of any other domain talk about. Still I wish I was a master of some trait, but cool.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When the summer breaks started I was willing to prepare for all the domains (SDE, finance, core, etc) for the campus internship drives to get any backup for next summer as most of them had just one prerequisite basically Competitive Programming. But I am glad I didn&amp;rsquo;t make that mistake and focussed on finding the domain suitable for me. I spent the vacation learning from MOOCS, building self projects and working on a sponsored research project. I participated in campus internship drive primarily for core electronics and R&amp;amp;D(in my field of interest). This Summer was definitely better than previous breaks.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I have/had many problems to deal with but I gained a bit of confidence in myself and was clear on some fundamentals to move ahead. Seeing people worried about CDC internship drives, some biases/preferences, some not so fair processes caused rift between many people, increased toxicity and through that I was able to see clearly that me or anyone else can&amp;rsquo;t change the process, the world is unfair we have to accept that and move ahead. I sat for some tests and 1 interview each on Day 1 and Day 2. I felt the fear of losing the day 1 chance at Google Hardware but the next day after losing Google Hardware, I was not so worried on Day 2 and got an offer from Texas Instruments. It was a long weekend but I was lucky to make it through. After that I have been looking for projects and research opportunities to work on, but I am out of ideas. I am confused again about what I should learn next ? Should I master core electronics or explore something new ? Becoz this is my last year to learn anything during undergrad (Pre-Final Year Undergrad).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The only thing I learnt from last 2 months is that, the beauty of time is that whether good or bad it passes away&amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Signing off &lt;br&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/Adiboy3112&#34;&gt;Aditya Ranjan Jha&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
